<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-26T15:38:06+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">catloaf &amp;amp; coffee</title><subtitle>An Autistic blog about being trans and stuff.</subtitle><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><entry><title type="html">Salem // Pyromania</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/salem-pyromania/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Salem // Pyromania" /><published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/salem-pyromania</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/salem-pyromania/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="salem">Salem</h2>
<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1598325836800-d7e85d803fad?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wzMDAzMzh8MHwxfHNlYXJjaHwxNHx8Ymxvb2QlMjBtb29ufGVufDB8fHx8MTc1NDM2NzU5NHww&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=1080" alt="sun setting over the clouds" /></p>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jaredmurray">Jared Murray</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/sun-setting-over-the-clouds-SCFtNxwLs8w">Unsplash</a></div>
<p>That place, a vampire<br />
Only the dead persist there<br />
Linger too long and join their ranks</p>

<p>They prey on those filled of hope<br />
With spirits unbroken<br />
Till nothing is left but a lifeless husk</p>

<p>At night they prowl<br />
Looking for the brightest of sparks<br />
Innocence makes the nectar sweeter</p>

<p>Deep do their fangs penetrate<br />
Crimson oozing down their chin<br />
Just another victim of circumstance</p>

<p>Seen it happen too many times<br />
Lost many a friend to that place<br />
Promised myself I wouldn’t meet the same fate</p>

<p>Felt myself withering<br />
Knew I couldn’t stay<br />
So I turned my back on everything</p>

<p>Under false pretenses I fled<br />
Claimed the spirit of adventure<br />
To elude suspicion</p>

<p>Found sanctuary in the unlikeliest of places<br />
Here, too, monsters roam the streets<br />
Just as lethal, somehow more manageable</p>

<p>Script has been flipped<br />
I am hunter, they are hunted<br />
Still I am not at ease</p>

<p>The beating of wings echoes on the horizon<br />
In the dark they creep closer<br />
It won’t be much longer now</p>

<p>Years they scoured the earth<br />
Looking for the one who escaped their grasp<br />
Sin so unforgivable, it cannot go unpunished</p>

<p>Trained for this moment, yet<br />
Fear clutches at my heart<br />
Though I will run no longer</p>

<p>Come, ye beasts!<br />
Come, ye vampires!<br />
Come, ye creatures of the night!</p>

<p>Unfinished business we must attend<br />
Ready thy fangs<br />
Prepare to meet thy maker<br />
<br /></p>
<h2 id="pyromania">Pyromania</h2>
<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1613216513535-6792472471c6?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wzMDAzMzh8MHwxfHNlYXJjaHw4fHxmaXJlJTIwZ3JhZGllbnR8ZW58MHx8fHwxNzU0Mjg5MzcyfDA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=1080" alt="orange and white abstract painting" /></p>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@flyd2069">FlyD</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/orange-and-white-abstract-painting-ESYU3GYbLHE">Unsplash</a></div>
<p>It’s funny<br />
They told you the truth<br />
Yet you kept on pretending like nothing happened</p>

<p>To be honest<br />
I don’t care about collateral anymore<br />
I’m ready to raze it all to the ground<br />
Just give me a reason</p>

<p>I’ll relish in the flames<br />
Let the fires warm my heart<br />
Watch the embers drift by<br />
Twinkling like fireflies<br />
Raise my arms high in victory<br />
And declare, <em>Liberation!</em></p>

<p>I’ve been dreaming of my demise since I turned nine<br />
Never thought I’d make it this far</p>

<p>Crawled from the deepest of depths<br />
Against all odds<br />
Bloody and broken<br />
And yet I remain</p>

<p>I wasn’t given a choice<br />
It was this or a noose<br />
I chose life</p>

<p>My existence<br />
An act of defiance<br />
A warning to any who dare stand in my way<br />
I will be denied no longer</p>

<p>Still you don’t understand what this is<br />
Still you fail to grasp the implications<br />
Still you refuse to recognize your complicity<br />
Still you shield your eyes from the pain you wrought</p>

<p>I am bitter<br />
I am angry<br />
I am hate</p>

<p>I have been denied life<br />
I have been denied a childhood<br />
I have been denied peace</p>

<p>You have denied me an identity<br />
For the sake of your ancient ideologies<br />
And absurd ideas about who I am or what I should be<br />
As if you had any fucking right</p>

<p>You, who cannot see the forest for the trees<br />
You, who is incapable of reckoning with their own behavior<br />
You, who has utterly failed to uphold the values you claim so dear<br />
You.</p>

<p>For this, you will be the recipient of my fury</p>

<p>Beware<br />
This is my calling card<br />
Deny me and be doomed<br />
Ere long you will lose that which you cannot replace</p>

<p>Soon we’ll be bathed in illustrious flame<br />
Flesh will give way to bone<br />
Bone will turn to ash<br />
And at last, I will be rid of you</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salem Photo by Jared Murray on Unsplash That place, a vampire Only the dead persist there Linger too long and join their ranks]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Old friends and bittersweet goodbyes at the Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/old-friends-and-bittersweet-goodbyes-at-the-hogwarts-school-of-witchcraft-and-wizardry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Old friends and bittersweet goodbyes at the Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry" /><published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/old-friends-and-bittersweet-goodbyes-at-the-hogwarts-school-of-witchcraft-and-wizardry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/old-friends-and-bittersweet-goodbyes-at-the-hogwarts-school-of-witchcraft-and-wizardry/"><![CDATA[<div class="fullwidth"><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1583997052301-0042b33fc598?q=80&amp;w=2832&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D" alt="Universal Studios Hogwarts castle" /></div>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jmeguilos">Jules Marvin Eguilos</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/brown-and-gray-concrete-castle-under-blue-sky-during-daytime-YrcfSDVli3Y">Unsplash</a></div>
<div class="contentWarning">J.K. Rowling</div>

<p>It’s Sunday. I’m visiting some family in Tokyo. The air is sweltering but I’m taking refuge at a small, beat-up dining table in my aunt’s and uncle’s house. Five of us are huddled around the table, eating French toast under a wall-mounted air conditioner unit. It softly hums away while the kids watch YouTube on an iPad and the adults deliberate what to do with our day.</p>

<p>We float through a few ideas, but nothing really sticks. How about that Godzilla exhibit, I say. Someone says they don’t like Godzilla. We could do teamLab,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> my uncle offers. Ah, never mind, tickets are sold-out. My aunt suggests Takeshita-dori.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> No one seems interested. What about a movie, my uncle proposes. No one even dignifies that with a response.</p>

<p>My uncle’s family is in Tokyo only temporarily. I’ve been visiting them each month, trying to make good use of the time that we have together. It’s been nice seeing my cousins. We’ve always been so far apart from each other—always on different hemispheres—that we’ve barely had any opportunities to interact.</p>

<p>Most of the contact I’ve had with them was when they were born. When I was in high school, I held the oldest in my arms right after he was born, and I saw the youngest for the first time over a video call when I was a freshman in university. She was so tiny then. Now, they’re both right in front of me watching a <em>Minecraft</em> “Let’s Play,” faces sticky from maple syrup. Babies no more. I feel old.</p>

<p>I have lots of these kinds of moments nowadays: Something reminds me of something else that in my mind is just a year-or-two old and then I realize it’s actually more like a full decade old except I can clearly remember when it was new and then I feel ancient and then I start to panic about my mortality and how I’ll be hitting 30 in just a couple of years and how I absolutely cannot be 30 and still a boy which shouldn’t actually be a problem because I’m transitioning but like, what if my transition is a failure?</p>

<p>I’m spiraling. I tell myself to calm down; that it’s a ridiculous thing to be having an existential crisis over some French toast at a comically small dining table at 10:30 in the morning. Deep breaths. Okay. I’m okay. I return to the present. We’ve still not settled on a plan for the day. I should probably think of some more ideas, else we might actually be here all day at this damn table. I love my uncle’s family, but settling on plans doesn’t seem to be their strong suit.</p>

<p>I know lots of places in Tokyo but I don’t normally have to consider children. Hmm. What do kids like? (God, I’m so old.) Well, my students love Harry Potter, and there’s that studio tour somewhere in Tokyo that we could go—the one with all the recreated sets from the movies that you can walk around on.</p>

<p>I ask if the kids like Harry Potter. They love Harry Potter, my uncle says. I tell him about the studio tour. He asks the kids if they want to go. The oldest says it sounds cool. The youngest asks what is Harry Potter?</p>

<p>They’ll love it, my uncle says, let’s do that.</p>

<p>We purchase tickets online, but our entry time is still a few hours away—a commonly used crowd-control tactic in Japan. We decide to bide our time by heading into Shinjuku for lunch and seeing the Godzilla statue there, because the kids haven’t seen it before.</p>

<p>Wait, didn’t someone say they don’t like Godzilla? I guess they changed their mind? I can’t keep up.</p>

<p>We take the train into Shinjuku. It is dirty and smells like shit, which is unusual for Tokyo but not for Shinjuku which is lined with bars as far as the eye can see. It’s not uncommon to stumble upon a puddle of vomit in the street here. It’s a lovely place.</p>

<p>While I guide everyone to the monster’s lair, the kids complain about the heat. It <em>is</em> hot. My clothes are starting to stick to my skin. I’m holding my pastel-pink umbrella aloft to provide some shade, but I can feel the band of my sports bra getting wetter by the second as beads of sweat run down my back. We haven’t even been outside for ten minutes. I love this country, but damn, is the summer intolerable.</p>

<p>Soon, we reach the famed Toho movie theatre with the great <em>kaiju</em> peaking over its top. A massive claw rests atop the theatre’s roof and a familiar round noggin floats above it. Its jaws are fixed open, frozen in a menacing grin. With its red eyes, it glares at the people meandering in the street below, going about their lives as if there isn’t a giant 20-story tall monster about to annihilate them all.</p>

<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1731658218464-51d8c83b55cb?q=80&amp;w=987&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D" alt="Godzilla looking down on Shinjuku street" /></p>
<div class="caption"><a href="https://unsplash.com/@jieyeu">Jie Yeu Teoh</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-city-street-filled-with-lots-of-tall-buildings-lOmsiNYE_o0">Unsplash</a></div>
<p>I happen to visit this theatre semi-regularly, so I’ve seen this sight a few dozen times before but I must admit, it <em>is</em> pretty cool. The kids think so, too, but only for about twenty seconds, after which we’re all standing on the street corner like, yep. That’s Godzilla.</p>

<p>It’s noon, so we head underground in pursuit of someplace to eat lunch. We settle on a restaurant that serves various standard Japanese-fare—<em>okonomiyaki</em>, <em>yakisoba</em>, and so on—and wait in line. Japan loves to queue. When people think of the Japanese Experience, they think of <em>geisha</em> and <em>kimono</em> and temples and <em>sakura</em>. But in reality, it often looks like staring at the back of a stranger’s head for hours on end—not exactly the exotic paradise everyone hopes for.</p>

<p>Waiting in line means we’re idle, and anyone who’s ever been around children knows that being idle is a very bad thing, indeed. Idle kids get bored, and bored kids aren’t something that anyone really wants, so my aunt takes the youngest to go look at some other restaurants in an attempt to bide our time, but this is an obvious rookie mistake. Article 237-C of the Hammurabi Code clearly states that one should never deviate from a plan once it is agreed upon by all children present. (Probably.)</p>

<p>Anyway, it’s too late. The restaurant we’re queueing at is deemed no longer acceptable.</p>

<p>The new plan is a curry and <em>onigiri</em> joint around the corner. We surrender our place in line and march over to this new place, and a problem immediately presents itself: it’s <em>tiny</em>. There’s no way the five of us could fit in there. So what now? Do we go back to the restaurant we just left? No, that’s stupid. And we’ve wasted so much time in our failed pursuit of food, that there isn’t much time left before we need to head to the studio tour.</p>

<p>Let’s just grab some onigiri and head over, my uncle says. We just ate breakfast, anyway.</p>

<p><em>Well</em>, this girlie is going through puberty again, and she could eat a whole-ass bear or two despite the French toast from a couple of hours ago. But she’s also a <em>lady</em>, so she’ll keep quiet about this to preserve the integrity of our expedition.</p>

<p>I sigh, but not loud enough for anyone to hear. I must express my dissatisfaction, but not in a confrontational way because I know I’m being a little unreasonable—just enough to make myself feel a little better about my lack of agency.</p>

<p>My uncle guides us through Shinjuku’s underbelly for like, 20 minutes to find an onigiri stand, which is odd considering onigiri is a dime-a-dozen in this country and we passed approximately 83 onigiri stands on the way to this one. This particular stand has a specialty for spicy tuna onigiri, which the kids seem excited about, at least. I reluctantly choose an onigiri made of fried rice, making sure to take a half-second longer to order so as to express my displeasure at this whole turn of events. We wolf down our snacks, then head over to the tour’s venue.</p>

<p>The site of “Warner Bros. Studio Tour Tokyo”—a name so obviously terrible it comes paired with a more descriptive subtitle, “The Making of Harry Potter,” which makes for an absurdly long title in full—is rather unassuming. A well-manicured lawn dotted with minimalist sculptures resembling various iconography from the Harry Potter films stretches out in front of a rather boring, boxy building. The only dead giveaway that we’re in the right place is the large Harry Potter logo above the entrance.</p>

<p>Yes, I kind of fucked up. We’re in Tokyo, one of the largest cities in the world, a place that <em>really does have it all</em>—and I bring everyone to the Harry Potter studio tour, of all places. We’re here because of <em>me</em>. <em>I</em> did this. Why is a trans girl suggesting we go somewhere built in honor of an IP that’s the product of <em>the</em> reigning TERF bitch? Look, estrogen makes you pretty, not smart. I wanted to see the kids happy and I panicked, okay? We couldn’t decide on anything, it’s our last weekend together before everyone leaves, and I just wanted to have a good time. I know I fucked up. I know.</p>

<p>And I’m regretting it already. Seeing that massive logo looming above me makes me feel strange, a bit uncomfortable. As we wait in line—because this is Japan, remember, we love to queue here—I look around me and everyone seems pretty damn straight and very cisgender. Meanwhile, here I am in a full face of makeup, a pink T-shirt with a cute cartoon bear on it, and breezy bottoms that no cisgender man would ever wear.</p>

<p>The Harry Potter logo looks upon me with disgust. <em>Tranny,</em> it jeers.</p>

<p>Shut up, Harry Potter logo. You’re just a sign.</p>

<p>While our tickets are scanned one-by-one, I anxiously consider what the insides of this building might contain. I hope it’ll be like the <em>Harry Potter 20th Anniversary</em> reunion, where everyone talked <em>around</em> J. K. Rowling, and anytime she did pop onscreen it was paired with a disclaimer that the segment was filmed years ago, as if the filmmakers were profusely apologizing for having to include her at all.</p>

<p>Yeah, I hope it’s like that.</p>

<p>It’s not like that. As soon as we enter the building, we’re greeted with a quote from one of the books, prominently displayed on a large banner and proudly attributed to the queen bitch herself. Oh god, what I have done.</p>

<p>We enter the main lobby: a cavernous carpeted space littered with benches and large LED displays running the length of its walls. To our left is a gift shop styled in the Ministry of Magic’s iconic green-and-black tile, to our right is a food court themed like Hogwarts’ Great Hall, and immediately ahead is a shadowy hole in the wall. Next to it sits a sign that reads, STUDIO TOUR ENTRANCE. We head straight there. I look longingly in the food court’s direction the whole way.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/studioTourMap.jpg" alt="map of Warner Bros. Studio Tour Tokyo" /></p>
<div class="caption">A map of Warner Bros. Studio Tour Tokyo. It fails to convey how truly massive a space it is. (Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.)</div>

<p>Beyond the ominous entrance lie massive on-set photos from each Harry Potter film, presented with a 3D-layered effect. My youngest cousin asks why there are cameras visible in some of the pictures, as if the tour creators made a glaring oversight. It’s a <em>studio</em> tour, I explain, we get to see how the movies were made! Oh, she says.</p>

<p>She’s adorable.</p>

<p>We’re corralled by staff into a dark rectangular room plastered with movie posters all along the front wall. My aunt points out one of the posters with Johnny Depp, and I say I don’t remember him in any of the films. He was in one of the <em>Fantastic Beasts</em> movies, she says. Oh, I say, I never saw those. She puffs out her bottom lip. That’s a shame, she says. They’re fun!</p>

<p>On the back wall is a row of portraits of all the films’ directors. At the end of the lineup is a familiar face: J. K. Rowling, with that stupid smirk that she always makes in photos. Can’t she just smile like a normal person? It isn’t that hard, girl.</p>

<p>I consider taking a picture of myself flipping off her portrait, but quickly abandon the idea as a large mass of people pushes into the space. The doors ahead are closed and we’re all standing around looking at these movie posters we’ve all seen a million times before. A staff member monologues about each of the posters. It’s very boring and very long. I’m not paying much attention because it’s all being conducted in Japanese and I don’t feel like applying my brain right now, and also I can’t shake the feeling of the hole being bored into my head from J. K. Rowling’s smug mug behind me.</p>

<p>Finally, the doors ahead are opened. Can we actually start the tour now? Nope. Instead, we’re being corralled into another dark and rectangular space. This room has a long LED screen spanning the width of the far wall, that shows Harry’s Japanese voice actor explaining the tour’s rules and teasing all the things we’re about to see.</p>

<p>Like, yeah dude, just let us see for ourselves. You don’t have to sell us on this. We’ve bought tickets already. Let us in!</p>

<p>The presentation ends with clips of fans dressed in wizard robes talking about what Harry Potter means to them. It feels like some weird corporate diversity video meant to show that <em>Harry Potter is for everyone</em>! I look around me. The room is very crowded—there’s probably a couple hundred people in here—but there’s not a single queer-presenting person in the room, save for me. I want to melt into a puddle and seep into the floor.</p>

<p>The doors ahead are opened and at last we can start- oh for fuck’s sake, Warner Brothers! Another dark rectangular room? I’m beginning to think this tour is just one big practical joke.</p>

<p>This room is much larger. It’s a cinema, complete with a large projection screen and several rows of theatre seats. We seat ourselves in the front row and Daniel Radcliffe, Rupert Grint, and Emma Watson (<em>queen</em>) appear onscreen to give an introduction to the tour. If my math is correct, this is now the third introduction to the tour (that everyone has already paid real money to attend) that we’re being subjected to. We “started” the tour 30 minutes ago. The kids are growing a little impatient. I am too.</p>

<p>Thankfully, this introduction is shorter than the others. The theatre screen is raised into the ceiling, and <em>behold!</em> The entrance doors to Hogwarts. It’s pretty cool, I must admit. We all crowd around the doors, and a staff member asks the crowd if anyone is celebrating a birthday or an anniversary. No one responds. He asks again. No one responds. He asks again. No one responds. He nervously chuckles to himself.</p>

<p>Refusing to be deterred, he asks for like, the fifth time. A child raises his hand and pushes through the crowd. The kid is maybe 12 years old. The staff member asks, <em>completely sincerely</em>, if today is his birthday or anniversary. I burst out laughing. No one else in the crowd offers even a hint of a laugh.</p>

<p>Kill me, kill me, kill me.</p>

<p>The kid is instructed to push open the doors at the count of three, but he doesn’t seem to understand much Japanese, and this staff member doesn’t know how to handle this. (I mean, who could possibly have foreseen that the big Harry Potter attraction would bring in overseas guests?) Eventually, they figure it out and the tour is allowed to begin at last. We shuffle through the double doors and into a recreation of Hogwarts’ Great Hall.</p>

<p>True to its name, it is pretty great. The floor is made of (fake) large stone slabs and the ceiling is simply bare lighting, just like the actual film set because the hall’s ceiling was added in post. The walls are lined with the hall’s iconic dining tables, and at each house’s section are mannequins donning their respective robes. At the far end of the hall, where the school’s staff would sit, is the Goblet of Fire. Two mannequins resembling Fred and George Weasley with long white beards are sprawled out on the floor in front of the artifact, recreating the scene from the fourth film.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/greatHall.jpg" alt="Hogwarts' Great Hall" /></p>
<div class="caption">Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.</div>

<p>A staff member approaches the goblet, introduces it, and then a burst of blue fire erupts from the goblet’s mouth. A little slip of paper shoots out from inside it and the staff member catches it in midair, gasps, and shows the paper to the crowd. It reads HARRY POTTER. Everyone claps. It’s very <em>sugoi</em>.</p>

<p>The kids are loving it. They’re excitedly bouncing around the hall, ooh-ing and ahh-ing at every little thing. There’s nothing quite like being a kid.</p>

<p>What’s that, the youngest asks. She points at some mannequins in green-and-black robes. That’s the Slytherin house, my uncle replies. They look bad, she says. Yeah, I say, they’re pretty bad. She bounces away to look at something else.</p>

<p>Once we’ve had our fill of the Great Hall, we move into the following rooms. We’re greeted with a behind-the-scenes look at the hall’s construction and then a room highlighting the iconic moving marble staircase. It’s been rebuilt here and it actually moves!</p>

<p>Next, is a large space showcasing the sets of the living areas at Hogwarts. There’s the Gryffindor and Slytherin common rooms, dorms, and Dumbledore’s office. Everything is just as I remember it from the films. Oh, there’s the fireplace where Harry spoke to Sirius in <em>Prisoner of Azkaban</em>! There’s where Ron and Harry argued about girls in <em>Goblet of Fire</em>. That’s the sword Harry uses in <em>Chamber of Secrets</em>.</p>

<p>Across from the Slytherin common room is an area where you can become spectators in a Quidditch match. The five of us are grouped up with about 15 others and are led onto a small set resembling the spectator stands from the films. We’re coached through various reactions while being filmed, then we’re guided to a display that shows a Quidditch scene from <em>Philosopher’s Stone</em> with our reactions cut in. It’s horribly cheesy, but the kids are going crazy for it.</p>

<p>I can’t stop looking at myself, though. Jesus Christ, I look like that? The camera caught me from a 45-degree angle and my side profile is dreadful. It’s so angular. It screams “man.” Gross. I feel sick.</p>

<p>Trying to hide my disgust, I cower in the back while everyone else laughs at the ridiculous edit on the display. After what feels like an eternity, the video ends and I shove past everyone, then hide in the Room of Requirement. Bad move. Everything here is reflective, and now I’m staring at my distorted face in various pots and pans. Ugly, ugly, ugly, they chant.</p>

<p>It would be brilliant if I could stop thinking about being trans for just a single minute. Every waking second of my existence is consumed with obsessive thoughts about how I look, how I sound, how I stand, how I walk, how I act. I look at everyone around me and compare myself to them, which is a very stupid thing to do, but as I previously established, this girlie isn’t the brightest.</p>

<p>And like, everyone in Tokyo is <em>so hot</em>. Both the women and the men. Everyone has these perfectly crafted outfits, glowing skin, and gorgeous hair. I want to be friends with all of them and learn their secrets. I want to date all of them and kiss them. I want to <em>be</em> them.</p>

<p>Then there’s me standing in front of an old chrome pot, staring at my warped face. I look like a blobfish.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/mrBlobby.jpg" alt="blobfish" title="it me" /></p>
<div class="caption">An actual picture of what I look like. Weren’t expecting a face reveal, I bet. (Kerryn Parkinson, <i>NORFANZ Expedition</i>)</div>

<p>The next part of the tour focuses on the learning environments at Hogwarts: Defense Against the Dark Arts and Potions classrooms, and the library. Wedged in between the classroom sets is the Mirror of Erised, in which Harry sees his parents in <em>Philosopher’s Stone</em>. At the studio tour, it’s been turned into a selfie opportunity. An orderly queue (I really wasn’t lying about Japan loving to queue) rests off to the side, with a long line of visitors patiently waiting for their turn. My aunt and uncle want a photo with everyone, so we take a place at the end of the line.</p>

<p>I am not thrilled about this, but what am I going to do? I’ve been running into this issue for my entire life: I’ve always <em>hated</em> taking photos, for reasons that should be obvious, but if I object to taking a photo everyone acts as if I personally insulted their mothers. I’ve learned to shut up and just go along with it. It’s easier that way.</p>

<p>As we wait for our turn, I try my best to dissociate. It works. Now I’m numb and I don’t really care about having to look at my reflection again. I watch my body from some high vantage point as we stand in front of the mirror. We smile, my uncle takes a couple of pictures, and then we give up our spot to the next group in line. My uncle shows us the photos. Everyone is smiling perfectly, looking so happy.</p>

<p>Isn’t it strange that we always smile in photos, even if we aren’t actually happy in the moment? We willingly choose to alter our memories of events, warping them with false records because god forbid we remember things as they actually happened. Our camera rolls depict much happier images of our lives than what actually occurred. It’s never made sense to me. The false smiles of mine that permeate the majority of the photos ever taken of me only remind me of just how unhappy or uncomfortable I actually was at the time. I can look at photos and recall the bullshit behind each smile: In this one, I said I didn’t want to be in the picture, and then there was a big argument about it right before we took the picture. Oh, in this one, I look super happy but really I was thinking about going home and hanging myself. Good times!</p>

<p>We proceed into the Forbidden Forest. Thick, towering trees surround us. The ground is a soft, squishy rubber made to look like dirt. In here, there are no reflective surfaces and everything is cast into shadow, so I’m able to slowly regain my composure. I watch the kids run about the forest, giggling with excitement. Screens are hung on the walls in between the trees to create the illusion of dementors flying through the woods. You can stand in front of these screens and mime a patronus charm to ward off the creatures. It’s a big hit with the kids.</p>

<p>After braving an encounter with the forest’s eight-legged inhabitants, we’re spit outside in front of Hagrid’s hut and a café behind it. A staff member informs us we’re at the halfway-point of the tour. Damn. We’ve spent nearly three hours here already.</p>

<p>We decide to eat lunch. For real this time. The café serves a host of themed foods, mostly consisting of British cuisine. I order the Slytherin plate: bangers and mash and an oolong tea. It’s <em>fine</em>. Definitely overpriced, but this is to be expected at a venue like this.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/cafeMenu.png" alt="Backlot Cafe menu" /></p>
<div class="caption">¥2,900 for mashed potatoes, peas, and a curly sausage? It’s a bit expensive by Tokyo standards. (Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.)</div>

<p>Before we commence the second half of the tour, I stop by the restroom. I hang a right to the men’s restroom because I’m not looking to start an <em>incident</em>, and lock myself in a stall. I hang my bag on the door’s hook and feel around inside for my mirror and lipstick, carefully reapply it, then brush my hair. This is a bit silly, really. There’s a huge mirror right outside, but instead I’m choosing to hide in a smelly stall to do my touch-ups. I’m still going to be walking around in the men’s restroom in a full face of makeup and feminine attire, but I guess it’s a step too far to openly reapply my lipstick.</p>

<p>Anxiety is stupid.</p>

<p>We resume our tour and arrive at Platform 9 ¾. The noble Hogwarts Express sits proudly at the station, steam billowing from its smokestack, impressing with its tremendous size. I stand in the middle of the platform, full of visitors going to-and-fro just like a real train platform, and it hits me:</p>

<p>Little Sage is <em>loving</em> this. She’s fan-girling <em>so hard</em> right now. This whole tour is basically all she ever wanted. Harry Potter was <em>everything</em> to me. I adored the books, and when I saw the movies it was like a religious experience. To now be walking around in the very spaces I read about is a dream come true.</p>

<p>Because they weren’t just books. They were a window to another world, another reality. A place where even the mundane was wondrous. A place where anything could—and did—happen. The Wizarding World was everything the real world wasn’t: Thrilling. Exciting. Happy. I wanted so badly to live there, and for most of my elementary school years I basically did.</p>

<p>I never had many friends. I still don’t. As it turns out, being Autistic and actually a girl (even though no one sees it, really) doesn’t make for a wealth of popularity. But at Hogwarts, I had Harry, Ron, and Hermione. I was right there with them—running all over the school grounds, getting into wacky hijinks, fighting Death Eaters, and drinking Butterbeer. They weren’t characters. They were <em>my friends</em>, and they accepted me even when no one else would.</p>

<p>But now, it’s all wrong. Here I am on Platform 9 ¾ and I should be over the moon, yet I feel so conflicted. Everywhere on this tour are various quotes from the books, all attributed to J. K. Rowling. Her dumb face pops up in various spots like a jump scare in some throwaway horror flick. She’s inescapable. This world that had played such a pivotal role in my formative years now feels nauseating. Normally, I’m a big proponent of separating the art from the artist, but Harry Potter has been steeped in its creator’s hate-fueled campaign for far too long to ignore. It’s wrong. We shouldn’t have come here. I shouldn’t have come here.</p>

<p>But still the tour continues. Now we’re walking on the green-and-black tiles of the Ministry of Magic. I stand in front of Dolores Umbridge’s pink dress, and it feels strangely fitting because by this point in the story the curtain has been lifted. After a brief stint as headmaster of Hogwarts, Umbridge is now in the belly of the authoritative Ministry of Magic and is no longer hiding her true nefarious nature; just as Rowling isn’t hiding her hatred for people like me. I think of her stupid cigar photo. She may as well be the one in this dress.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/jkrowlingCigar-Censored.jpg" alt="JK Rowling smoking cigar with devil horns and eyes crossed out" title="bitch." /></p>
<div class="caption">Following the UK’s Supreme Court ruling that the term “woman” does not apply to trans women, Rowling posted this image (edits mine) with the caption: “I love it when a plan comes together.” Cunt. (<a href="https://x.com/jk\_rowling/status/1912644919103004807">J.K. Rowling on X</a>)</div>

<p>I don’t know whether I want to scream, cry, or both, but I decide that the cold interior of the Ministry isn’t the place for either of those things. We meander through a section showing how the books’ magical creatures were realized on screen, and then we hop in line for the Broomstick Experience. First, a staff member takes a group photo (ugh) and then whisks us away to a green stall with a broomstick suspended horizontally. My oldest cousin mounts it and is instructed to give various reactions and poses, while he’s superimposed into a scene from <em>Goblet of Fire</em> where Harry flys away from a dragon, except instead of Harry it’s now my cousin. Everyone laughs. The youngest especially.</p>

<p>It’s my uncle’s turn. He makes crazy, exaggerated movements and the kids are bowled over with laughter. He’s a good dad. I’m laughing, too, but only because I’m trying to blend in. Really, I’m dreading being asked to get on the broomstick because I don’t think I can handle seeing myself on camera again.</p>

<p>The staff member motions for me to enter the stall. I politely decline. Everyone seems a little bummed.</p>

<p>I am, too. I feel like a disappointment. I wish I wasn’t like this.</p>

<p>We’re almost finished now. Just two main features to go. After the Broomstick Experience is an exhibit explaining foley-work, and then <em>there it is</em>: Diagon Alley.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/diagonAlley.jpg" alt="Diagon Alley" /></p>
<div class="caption">Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.</div>

<p>Of all the books’ many locales, this is certainly the most whimsical, which is probably why this set was saved for last. Its winding path stretches out in front of us, utilizing a bit of forced perspective that makes it all seem at least twice as big as it really is. Just like in the films, shops are jammed haphazardly together, painted in all sorts of vibrant colors, and constructed in impossible geometry. I waltz over to 93 Diagon Alley, where Weasley &amp; Weasley is located. Inside are endless shelves of multicolored boxes paired with zany signs detailing their contents. In the middle of the shop floor is a statue of a child holding a large bowl containing purple-and-green candies. The statue has a concerningly round head and is hunched over the bowl, mouth unnaturally agape, as a steady flow of the candies expel from its orifice into the bowl. Beside the statue is a sign that reads PUKING PASTILLES. I feel a strange sense of kinship with the thing.</p>

<p>The set is immaculately kept and exhaustively detailed, but I’m quite tired of this place. I’m ready to leave, and not just because I feel <em>weird</em> about being trans at Hogwarts. We’ve been here for over five hours now. As impressively comprehensive a tour as this is, it is <em>so very long</em>.</p>

<p>Luckily, there’s only one stop left in our tour. We pass through a hallway featuring a spread of the Marauder’s Map to the tour’s final chamber. It is a vast, black chamber housing a staggeringly massive model of the Hogwarts grounds in full. It’s difficult to convey the size of it. The room is essentially two or three stories tall. We enter at the top and <em>still</em> the model towers before us. It’s a brilliant finale, even if it does feel hollow.</p>

<p>At long last, our tour has come to a close. We’re spit out into the gift shop, which is inexplicably larger than the Great Hall and Diagon Alley sets combined. I peruse the merchandise while the kids sort through plushies. There are wands, robes, hats, building sets, pins, stationary, confectionaries, Butterbeer, figures—far too much to list off, even if I could remember all of the shop’s offerings. I cannot deny that this stuff is cool. It’s not junk. It’s quality stuff. I would totally buy an irresponsible amount of merch, if it weren’t for J. K. Rowling’s stench plaguing everything in sight.</p>

<p>It’s past six now. We decide we may as well grab dinner before we leave, so we walk to the dining hall styled like Hogwarts’ Great Hall. I order an English breakfast, which like the bangers and mash, is aggressively overpriced. The toast is branded with “9 ¾” in a meager attempt to tie the meal into the theming. It tastes like styrofoam. It’s a bit sad.</p>

<p>I finish my meal before everyone else because I ordered first. In Japan, meals are brought out whenever they’re ready so usually you eat when your food arrives, even if other members in your party are still waiting to receive their order. I watch the kids eat. Somehow, they appear to be getting just as much food in their mouths as on their faces.</p>

<p>Our kids have the worst table manners, my uncle says. I chuckle. It’s gross but also cute, in a little kid sort of way.</p>

<p>Eventually, watching the messy display in front of me grows old, so I look around the room. We’re sat close to where the dining hall meets the main lobby. I look toward the exit. Above it is a quote immortalized in golden letters that reads, WHETHER YOU COME BACK BY PAGE OR BY THE BIG SCREEN, HOGWARTS WILL ALWAYS BE THERE TO WELCOME YOU HOME. In small letters below, the quote’s author is revealed: J. K. Rowling.</p>

<p>Those words were originally spoken nearly 15 years ago, during the premiere of the <em>Deathly Hallows: Part 2</em>. It was a simpler time when the Wizarding World yet lacked the political undertones it carries today. Rowling’s hatred of the trans community wouldn’t come to light until many years later. But in 2025, the quote suspended above takes on a more nuanced meaning: Hogwarts will always be there to welcome you, except for me because I am trans.</p>

<p>I get up from the table and capture the only photo I take of the entire tour. I lazily position the quote in frame and then my right hand with its middle finger extended. Like our group photo at the Mirror of Erised, it paints a false image of the current moment. It implies anger and defiance, but I feel neither of these things. I’m just sad, and tired. Tired of being sad.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/hogwarts/jkrowlingFuckYou.jpg" alt="my middle finger extended to J.K. Rowling's quote" title="bullshit!" /></p>

<p>I look back to my cousins in the dining hall, still painting their faces with their dinner. They’re so innocent, so beautifully oblivious to the sinister bigotry lurking behind everything around us. They are free to run about and take everything at face-value. They don’t have to hyper-analyze everything for its subtext, or consider whether they should even be here at all. Hogwarts is just a magical school from some old movies. Dobby is just a funny little guy. J. K. Rowling is just a face on a wall. I envy them.</p>

<p>For many trans people—and Autistics, of which I am one—childhood is a blur. I don’t remember my childhood much. I remember only a few things: a constant state of unease, the resulting persistent desire to no longer exist, weirdness from growing up in the church. It’s difficult to recall anything especially positive, but Harry Potter has always been one of the few exceptions. Now, I don’t even have that.</p>

<p>We exit the tour building. The front lawn is now illuminated by moonlight. As we walk to the nearby train station, my aunt asks if I’ll finally watch the <em>Fantastic Beasts</em> movies.</p>

<p>No, I say, I don’t think I will.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>teamLab is a popular art installation in Tokyo with a host of 3D interactive light displays. It’s hard to explain without pictures, but it’s super cool. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>The main street in Harajuku, an area in Shibuya known for its fashion. Its heyday was in the early aughts, but it’s still a major tourist destination. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="trans" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo by Jules Marvin Eguilos on Unsplash J.K. Rowling]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Baptize me in that purple-pink girlypop glow.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/baptize-me-in-that-purple-pink-girlypop-glow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Baptize me in that purple-pink girlypop glow." /><published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/baptize-me-in-that-purple-pink-girlypop-glow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/baptize-me-in-that-purple-pink-girlypop-glow/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/planetariumWide.jpg" alt="Maddy in planetarium" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<div class="spoilerWarning">Vague spoilers for <i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>.</div>
<div class="infoWarning">Originally posted on <a href="https://letterboxd.com/neko_and_co/film/i-saw-the-tv-glow/5/">Letterboxd</a>, with a bit of added polishing for <b>catloaf &amp; coffee</b>.</div>

<p>Once one pushes past the initial fear, starting transition is exciting. It’s time to start hormones, buy new clothes, try a new hairstyle, learn makeup, and get a piercing or two. Eventually, though, some time passes and one has checked all those little boxes, and now there’s not much left to do but wait.</p>

<p>Five months into my transition, I’m feeling the lull set in. Of course, I can still work on my wardrobe and makeup skills and so on. But the initial rush of euphoria that comes along with all those “firsts” has come and gone. Now I’m left to slowly watch myself change in the mirror. It’s tough. I didn’t realize how heavily I’d been relying on the highs of that initial transition period, so as I move into this next phase of my transition, I’ve found myself feeling especially dysphoric. Many a day has gone by where I’m at the verge of tears at every hour of the day.</p>

<p>Frustrated and wanting to <em>do something</em> to further my progress, I was playing around with FaceApp’s feminization filter, hoping it would provide pointers on what I should focus on. (Yes, consulting an AI-powered filters app for tips on my transition is almost certainly a bad idea, but I was feeling desperate.) After feeding it a few pictures of myself from the past year, I came to a curious realization: in recent pictures, the filter barely touched my face at all and just gave me longer hair. But in pictures from the start of my transition, the filter changed my whole face. This made me feel a bit better about my progress. It helped me to see the genuinely substantial changes I’ve undergone in a mere five months. Of course, I’m still not anywhere near where I want to be—hell, the app itself assumes my gender as male—but it was nice to be able to recognize the progress I’ve made.</p>

<p>Even so, the filter’s recommendation was to grow my hair out longer. Fair enough. I’d already been considering doing so, however this meant more waiting around for things to happen… not exactly the brilliant action-packed plan I was hoping for.</p>

<p>I was feeling lost. I felt myself beginning to slip as doubt crept in. <em>You’ll never be a girl. You’ll always just be a dude in makeup.</em></p>

<p>I needed guidance, and there was only one place I could think of to go: <em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>.</p>

<div class="break"><img src="/assets/images/break-beans.png" /></div>

<p>I pushed play. <em>Let’s go to church.</em></p>

<p>Two minutes into the runtime, a gym class parachute lined with white, blue, pink, and purple stripes billows through the air as <em>Anthems For A Seventeen Year-Old Girl</em> by yeule hums in the background. I can feel it hitting already. My face is scrunched up, I’m sniffling, tears running down my cheek. It’s an ugly sight, I’m sure, but no one is around. It’s just me, my cat plushie, and <em>TV Glow</em>.</p>

<p>Soon, Caroline Polachek sings of girls with makeup in <em>Starburned and Unkissed</em> as Owen strolls through his high school’s hallways. I’m losing it. In my first viewing, I cried here, too—albeit with far fewer tears, as I was emotionally stunted then. But tonight, with testosterone eradicated, my lips are wet and taste of salt. Tonight, <em>I am</em> one of the girls in makeup.</p>

<p>Ere long, it’s time for Maddy’s monologue, and I swear this is the greatest monologue ever committed to film and <em>I will fight anyone who says otherwise</em>. Maddy literally looks into the camera and says they pissed and shit their pants and it somehow works. I don’t understand <em>how</em> it works, only that it does. <em>Bravo</em>, Jack Haven.</p>

<p>(<em>For the steaming pile of dog shit that is</em> Emilia Pérez <em>to have been nominated for Best Picture and not this is perhaps one of the greatest travesties of our times. Then again, maybe no one should care about an award show that only started <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/04/22/nx-s1-5372650/oscar-voting-changes">requiring its judges to actually watch the films</a> they vote on after 97 whole-ass years. I digress.</em>)</p>

<p>(<em>Actually, one more thing. Did you know <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/news/general-news/zoe-saldana-emilia-perez-oscar-trans-1235131572/">Zoe Saldaña’s Oscar statue is trans</a>? It goes by they/them. Yes, the statue. Thank you, Zoe Saldaña, very cool. Next time you want to give a nod to the marginalized community that the film you won an award for centers around, try doing so in your <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aeCv6NyMveg">acceptance speech</a>. You know, the place where you’ll have the most eyeballs? I. Digress.</em>)</p>

<p>As Maddy delivers their speech in the planetarium, I feel something welling up inside of me. So many emotions. Fear? Hopelessness? Denial? No. Once, these were the things I felt in response to this film, but no longer. Tonight, I feel happy. Hopeful. Grateful for having seen this film and absorbed its teachings. Joyful for having finally discovered myself; for starting season six.</p>

<p>The tears are rushing down my face now. My nose is oozing down my upper lip, and I taste a rather off-putting concoction of salty tears and bitter mucus. My eyes feel swollen. I’m going through it, girl.</p>

<p>I start shaking. I can’t control it. I’m squeezing this plushie within an inch of its nonexistent life and I’m wildly shaking. In this moment, I feel Maddy’s every word. Every breath. Every step. This feeling is so intense I feel like I might burst. It’s overwhelming. I can barely handle it.</p>

<p>The monologue ends. My heart feels like it’s about to burst out of my chest but I slowly calm down.</p>

<p>Now Owen is screaming in the Fun Center’s party room. Last year, this scene shook me to my core. Tonight, I watch in sadness for Owen, but feel at ease knowing that I’ve spared myself this fate.</p>

<div class="break"><img src="/assets/images/break-beans.png" /></div>

<p>Words cannot begin to express how much this film means to me. I know because I’ve been trying to put its impact on me into words ever since I first saw this film back in October. I wrote an <a href="/2025/i-saw-the-tv-glow-and-it-terrified-me/">8,000 word personal essay</a> using <em>TV Glow</em> as a framework for my own coming out story, and much to my chagrin it completely fails at communicating the transcendent power this film holds for me. The English language simply doesn’t possess the verbiage—and I, the writing prowess—to convey these emotions.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, here I am trying to convey them yet again. Despite having seen <em>TV Glow</em> six times now and having poured over its script countless times when writing that aforementioned essay, this most recent viewing drew out an emotional response in me greater than ever before. Its magic isn’t fading. Not even a little.</p>

<p>I’m just… <em>so fucking happy</em> to be where I am now. I’m learning to love myself, and I owe it all to this film—to Jane Schoenbrun, to Jack Haven, to Justice Smith; everyone who made this work of art possible. This film birthed me a new life.</p>

<p><em>I Saw the TV Glow</em> and trembled before God while she smiled back at me. Nothing was the same since.</p>

<p>June 16, 2025</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="trans" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I Saw the TV Glow, A24]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">untitled01</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/untitled01/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="untitled01" /><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/untitled01</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/untitled01/"><![CDATA[<p>mass fatality capitalist brutality southern hospitality twisted rationality cult of personality presidential criminality comprised morality puritanical sexuality pedophilic carnality claim it as spirituality // <strong>make it stop</strong> // illegal immigration failed assassination violent inflammation forced exhalation sensory deprivation self-flagellation unholy exaltation rally the congregation trans subjugation eternal damnation // <strong>make it stop</strong> // assisted suicide executive homicide looming tyrannicide racist countryside kings deified memes deep fried pass the cyanide nitrous oxide entry denied dolls crucified // <strong>make it stop</strong> // genitalia mutilated government x-rated ego inflated public agitated masterfully baited economy decapitated biblically indoctrinated emotionally constipated criminally implicated survivor designated // <strong>make it stop</strong> // military mandate media magnate prematurely ejaculate Andrew Tate police state consumed with hate publicly humiliate diplomatic checkmate rising mortality rate mentally degenerate // <strong>make it stop</strong> // waiting for the all clear ultra-right beer bullshit veneer freedom insincere connections peer-to-peer wartime profiteer fiscal year smug sneer shed a tear kill the queer // <strong>make it stop</strong> // project 2025 kick the beehive nazis in overdrive reputation nosedive warcrimes on TikTok live barely alive just trying to survive praying on the DSM-5 encrypted hard drive backup archive // <strong>make it stop</strong> // domestic terrorism vaccines and autism give me an exorcism transsexual fetishism tyrannical nationalism sanctimonious evangelism apathetic autoeroticism flagrant orientalism grotesque individualism sterile neoliberalism // <strong>make it stop</strong> // doom impending government spending senators condescending children gender-bending police apprehending thoughts and prayers extending headlines never-ending WASP defending nazi salutes trending lives upending // <strong>make it stop</strong> // another deadname playing the numbers game rejected insurance claim hack the mainframe subliminal shame aliens to blame head first into the door frame slurs to reclaim felonies to disclaim Donald just came // <strong>make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[mass fatality capitalist brutality southern hospitality twisted rationality cult of personality presidential criminality comprised morality puritanical sexuality pedophilic carnality claim it as spirituality // make it stop // illegal immigration failed assassination violent inflammation forced exhalation sensory deprivation self-flagellation unholy exaltation rally the congregation trans subjugation eternal damnation // make it stop // assisted suicide executive homicide looming tyrannicide racist countryside kings deified memes deep fried pass the cyanide nitrous oxide entry denied dolls crucified // make it stop // genitalia mutilated government x-rated ego inflated public agitated masterfully baited economy decapitated biblically indoctrinated emotionally constipated criminally implicated survivor designated // make it stop // military mandate media magnate prematurely ejaculate Andrew Tate police state consumed with hate publicly humiliate diplomatic checkmate rising mortality rate mentally degenerate // make it stop // waiting for the all clear ultra-right beer bullshit veneer freedom insincere connections peer-to-peer wartime profiteer fiscal year smug sneer shed a tear kill the queer // make it stop // project 2025 kick the beehive nazis in overdrive reputation nosedive warcrimes on TikTok live barely alive just trying to survive praying on the DSM-5 encrypted hard drive backup archive // make it stop // domestic terrorism vaccines and autism give me an exorcism transsexual fetishism tyrannical nationalism sanctimonious evangelism apathetic autoeroticism flagrant orientalism grotesque individualism sterile neoliberalism // make it stop // doom impending government spending senators condescending children gender-bending police apprehending thoughts and prayers extending headlines never-ending WASP defending nazi salutes trending lives upending // make it stop // another deadname playing the numbers game rejected insurance claim hack the mainframe subliminal shame aliens to blame head first into the door frame slurs to reclaim felonies to disclaim Donald just came // make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop make it stop]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sad Bitch Hour: It’s Dysphoria Weekend™</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/sad-bitch-hour-its-dysphoria-weekend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sad Bitch Hour: It’s Dysphoria Weekend™" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/sad-bitch-hour-its-dysphoria-weekend</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/sad-bitch-hour-its-dysphoria-weekend/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/sadBitchHour/sadBitchHourHeader.png" alt="rainy, happy devil, and lipstick emojis" /></p>

<div class="contentWarning">Does this need a content warning? I don’t know. Listen honey, this piece is full of bitterness and resentment and hostility and a general disdain for any and all life. If you’re not in a good place to receive that, skip this one! And if you are in a good place, hey, maybe skip this one anyway! You’ve got better things to do, I promise.<br /><br />

And like, obviously this post isn’t safe for work, but if you clicked on a post titled “Sad Bitch Hour” thinking it’d be safe for work, who’s the clown here? It ain’t me, sister.</div>

<p>Sorry, what’s that?</p>

<p>How’s the transition going, you ask?</p>

<p>Oh girl, you want to know?</p>

<p>Are you sure?</p>

<p>You <em>really</em> want to know?</p>

<p>You <em>really, really</em> want to know?</p>

<p>Alright, I’ll tell you.</p>

<p>But just remember, <em>you asked for this</em>…</p>

<p><strong>Welcome to my waking nightmare.</strong></p>

<div class="break"><img src="/assets/images/break-beans.png" /></div>

<p>Ugh. Fuck, why? Why??</p>

<p>To my great displeasure, I have awoken in yet another day. Today it is Sunday, which means it’s the second part of this <em>wondrous</em> weekend I’m having. Yesterday was shit but maybe today will be better?</p>

<p>Of course it fucking won’t. It’s 2025, girl! We’re all rapidly plummeting toward the-world-as-we-know-it’s death and the brakes failed ages ago. It only gets worse from here. Welcome to the new normal. Put on your big girl panties.</p>

<p>(Or don’t actually, because you still have your male appendage so you sure as hell aren’t gonna fit in them.)</p>

<p>I pull out my phone and start my morning scroll. Yeah, yeah, doomscrolling is bad for you, but don’t worry I know what I’m doing because I heard about something called <em>exposure therapy</em> once.</p>

<p>I’m on reddit because I guess I hate myself, or maybe I have an unexplored masochism kink. Both are equally likely. My feed is comprised of cat photos, some whining about the <em>absolute state</em> of various video games, and a whole lot of trans-related posts. Posts like:</p>

<p><em>Someone called me Ms. at work and I really liked it, am I trans?</em></p>

<p><em>I want to cry every time I look in the mirror, what’s wrong with me?</em></p>

<p><em>I’m dating this girl who thought she was a lesbian until she met me and she says I’m not like other guys, what does this mean?</em></p>

<p><em>My boyfriend said I’ll never be a woman and called me a tranny, is he being transphobic?</em></p>

<p>God, this shit is like, <em>so 2024</em>. Bitch, you’re trans. The answer is always that you’re trans and you should break up with your boyfriend. Or something. Whatever. I don’t care.</p>

<p>Today, I do not care. Today, I regret waking up.</p>

<p>I think I’m at a low point in my transition, honestly. I’ve ticked off a lot of the easy boxes like buying new clothes, learning makeup, and getting my ears pierced. Now I’m left with the hard, not-so-fun, long-term stuff like laser hair removal (maybe one day I won’t be a broke bitch and can afford it) and voice training and growing my hair out and just fucking waiting around for hormones to do their thing. I can actually see the girl in the mirror now—whoop-de-fucking-doo—but it’s basically just a waiting game until I actually reach her.</p>

<p>And goddamn, haven’t I waited long enough? Get off your ass, girl! Why are you making me chase you? Meet me halfway, at least. Fuck.</p>

<p>I wallow in my misery underneath my weighted blanket for a while. I need to go into the city today to buy a business casual outfit—or “cool biz” as it’s known in Japan—for a conference on Tuesday. The only clothes I have that fit the bill are from pre-transition when I was bloated to all hell, and honey we can’t be having any of that now, can we?</p>

<p>Thinking about going out into public like <em>this</em> makes me want to die, though. So I present an incredible offer to my rational brain (RB): what about today’s shopping, <em>tomorrow</em>? That’s good. God, I’m so innovative. Steve Jobs should hire me.</p>

<p>Alright, it’s a stupid fucking idea, but it’s exactly the kind of stupid fucking idea that I’m currently prone to going along with, and sure enough RB falls for it. Ha, dumbass! Not even estrogen can vanquish the procrastinator within me.</p>

<p>I should probably actually do something with my day, though. I may be a sad bitch, but I at least have enough sense to realize that wallowing around in bed all day isn’t actually as intelligent of a plan as I might think. Get up_,_ RB commands. Ugh. Just a few more minutes. Get the fuck up, RB screams. Fine, I’ll get up but you didn’t have to be a bitch about it. I was gonna get up anyway. Eventually.</p>

<p>I drag myself to the mirror and like, how the fuck do you think I feel about what I see? Dark bags under my eyes like I’m a drug addict, and two day’s worth of beard growth because I felt so gross yesterday that I couldn’t be fucked to even bother shaving. I mean, what’s even the point if I’m just going to look like a dude anyway? At best, maybe I can look like a fag, but you know that’s not really the reason I started transition, is it? No one had any problem with pinning me as a fag before I started transitioning, anyhow.</p>

<p>Whatever. Today, I don’t care about those things. Dysphoria? Ha, who’s she?</p>

<p>I step into the shower, which I’ve grown to have a very love/hate relationship with because I can look down at my feet and BEHOLD! <em>Tits!</em> … and a dick. Yes, this is what I am now. Somewhere between man and woman. A weird transsexual freak.</p>

<p>At least no one can tell if you’re crying when you’re in the shower. Haha!</p>

<p>Shower’s over and I’m feeling like maybe I should try actually combating my dysphoria by trying to look good, instead of just throwing on a depression hoodie like yesterday. I switch on my razor and get to shaving. Little cuts start to appear across my face because that’s just what happens when you shave, I guess? I mean, it’s 2025, you’d think we’d have a better way of shaving without destroying your face but I guess my face is just too sensitive, so fuck me. Better to look a little cut up than to have a beard? I guess?</p>

<p>????</p>

<p>While my face dries from that balm I slather all over my face in the hopes that it’ll prevent my face from turning bright red and bumpy after shaving, but in reality my face still turns red and bumpy only a little bit less so than without it, I look through my wardrobe. It’s really stupid. 70% of my clothes are from pre-transition and I treat them like they’re coated in the bubonic plague. Thing is, plenty of clothes in that 70% are still perfectly fine to wear, but nope. Can’t do it. Won’t do it. They have that filthy fucking boy stench all over them. Instead, I stick to my new clothes that don’t fit me right. You know, the ones designed for hips I don’t have? The ones that assume a bust I don’t have? The ones tailored without a cock in mind? Yes, those.</p>

<p>Last week, a friend asked me why don’t I ever wear a dress? Fair question. A dress wouldn’t have the bulge issue. Still, it’s not going to happen. You will never see me in a dress, I said, not for a very long time. Why not, they asked. I sighed and explained that if I put on a dress and look in the mirror and see a dude in a dress, I think I might just go postal.</p>

<p>If I’m going to try to combat my dysphoria today, I suppose I ought to choose something that’ll make me feel like not-a-dude. How about that skirt that I bought and vowed to never let a single other soul ever see me in because I have a crushingly pathetic sense of self-confidence? Well, I didn’t shave my legs today, so that’s out. Whatever, it’s Sunday and I’m not stepping foot outside. A cami and those pants I bought at H&amp;M that I got really excited about because <em>oh my god I’m wearing girl pants for the first time</em> and then subsequently <em>mortified</em> once I put them on again at home and saw a clear outline of my schlong—yeah, those’ll do. Who cares.</p>

<p>I return to the mirror and push play on my “<a href="https://music.apple.com/jp/playlist/bad-girl-club/pl.u-yZyVVaZIY4lWLya?l=en">Bad Girl Club</a>” playlist which is supposed to be affirming and empowering, but today it just feels like it’s mocking me for being bad at being a girl. Which, fair enough. I mean, I can’t really argue with that.</p>

<p>Time for makeup. I decide to try a darker eye shadow today to reflect all these capital-F “Feelings” swirling around inside of me, like I’m Robert Pattinson in <em>The Batman</em>, which is a very funny analogy because he is a boy and I am not really. I carelessly smear it over my eyelids and add in some eyeliner with a pen. I’ve never been very good with the pen and today is no exception but fuck it, it doesn’t matter because today I do not care.</p>

<p>Delilah Bon’s aggressively feminist <em>Dead Men Don’t Rape</em> blares out my speakers and girl, it’s a vibe. I don’t know if it’s a good one, but it’s definitely <em>a vibe</em>.</p>

<p>Finished, I look at myself in the mirror. My eye shadow is all over the place and it’s way too dark for my protruding eyebrow bone that already casts my eyes into shadow. My eyeliner looks like a five-year-old’s crayon disasterpiece that they did on the wall while Mommy wasn’t looking. I look like shit. <em>It’s perfect</em>.</p>

<p>Now’s the point in my morning routine where I take a selfie to document my transition. I tell myself this is a really good idea, but so far I’m not really convinced. It mostly just makes me feel worse about myself, if you can believe that, but yesterday I managed to take a photo so today certainly isn’t going to be the day when I fuck up my 150+ day streak. I put on my best bitchy face and flip off the camera, as a notification from the Associated Press pops down: <em>The U.S. attacked three Iranian nuclear sites, Trump says, joining Israeli air campaign as Tehran promises to retaliate.</em></p>

<p>Yeah, sure, fuck it. Why not? Not like it’s a surprise, I mean we all knew this was going to happen as soon as Trump started talking in pluralities, right? And what’s another war, anyway? America’s kill count is like its financial debt: too fucking high for anyone to understand or give a shit about. Like, 30 trillion dollars? What does that even <em>mean</em>?</p>

<p>So fuck it, what’s a few more bodies, right? What’s more American than blood in the Middle East?</p>

<p>I’m firmly atheist, except for today. Today, I believe in Hell and I’m in it.</p>

<p><em>Hey Luci</em>, I say with a flirty wave.</p>

<p><em>Hey girlie,</em> he says. His horns look extra delicious today. Damn, he could <em>totally</em> hit, I mean, if he wanted to.</p>

<p><em>Bet you’re loving all this, huh, babe?</em></p>

<p><em>Girl, you don’t even know! That prick is bringing me so much business. We’re having to work overtime just to accommodate all these MAGA fucks!</em></p>

<p><em>That’s great, hun,</em> I say. <em>You gonna have my E ready for me this month?</em></p>

<p><em>Of course, of course,</em> he says with a hand wave. <em>What do you think I am, some kinda shady back alley dealer? I’ve never let you down.</em> He pauses and raises an eyebrow. <em>Assuming you’re good on quota this month?</em></p>

<p><em>Naturally. Wouldn’t dream of shorting you, my dear.</em></p>

<p>He smiles. <em>That’s my girl!</em></p>

<p>(All trans girls get their estrogen from Satan in exchange for spreading the trans agenda. You didn’t know that? Oh my god, that’s <em>so</em> embarrassing for you.)</p>

<p>I sit my bony ass down in front of my computer. What’s nice about the Internet is it makes it easy to hyper-focus, and then I get so absorbed into whatever it is that I’m doing that I start to meld with the 1’s and 0’s and I can leave behind my corporeal flesh. Lately, I’ve been feeling all sorts of emotions which is theoretically what I wanted when I started HRT, but then again maybe not like this? There was a weird, fucked up sense of peace in feeling numb all the time, at least.</p>

<p>Anyway, it doesn’t really matter because I’d sooner fucking die than go back to the way things were before. I still believe this, even if today I’d rather bury myself in the nearest rice paddy for a few years. Maybe the next few decades. It’d save everyone the trouble of digging me a grave. I’d probably be better at being fertilizer than a girl, anyhow.</p>

<p>So, I beg the Internet to bludgeon my senses until I’m a Pretty Girl. Except instead of playing a game or watching YouTube until my brain rots away, today I decide to write—an unusual decision, as I never write on the weekends. However, today I have Important Words that must be expressed. It’s <em>imperative</em> that the three people that read the things I write hear about-</p>

<p>Well actually, given the horrifying headline I just received on my phone, this isn’t important in the slightest. But what else am I, a sad bitch in her sadder apartment, going to do? No, today I write because fuck you.</p>

<p>I navigate to some pretentious blog with a cat in a coffee cup as its logo and start a new post. I give it some dramatic and slightly provocative title, and a subtitle containing a reference that most people probably won’t even get because I guess I like to see how far I can crawl up my own ass.</p>

<p>I’ll look at it later and roll my eyes, I’m sure.</p>

<p>But today, I do not give a fuck.</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="trans" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The coup will be televised.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/the-coup-will-be-televised/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The coup will be televised." /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/the-coup-will-be-televised</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/the-coup-will-be-televised/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1557992260-ec58e38d363c?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wzMDAzMzh8MHwxfHNlYXJjaHwyfHxuZXdzJTIwZmlyZXxlbnwwfHx8fDE3NDk3ODU5NzF8MA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=1080" alt="man sitting on chair holding newspaper on fire" /></p>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@pixel_talkies">Nijwam Swargiary</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/man-sitting-on-chair-holding-newspaper-on-fire-FPNnKfjcbNU">Unsplash</a></div>

<p>Corpses pile up in the Middle East, in 4K they’re caught<br />
Don’t you dare call it a genocide<br />
Lest you’re shipped off to CECOT</p>

<p>In Europe, drones buzz overhead<br />
Death following in their wake<br />
The world looks on and goes to bed<br />
Later donates to the cause for a tax break</p>

<p>Eleven slain in Graz<br />
Cold on the classroom floor<br />
There’s no just cause<br />
Never enough uproar</p>

<p>The Witch Queen sits upon her throne<br />
With a proud smirk and cigar in hand<br />
All the while the dolls groan —<br />
Just as planned</p>

<p>Airplanes falling from the sky<br />
We hebben een serieus probleem<br />
Blame it on DEI<br />
I’ll light the candelabrum</p>

<p>Bro’s got worms<br />
But he’s in charge of our health?<br />
Probably doesn’t even believe in germs<br />
(Or the commonwealth)</p>

<p>The leader of the free world perverts and goads<br />
While the spaceman grovels at his feet<br />
Oh dear, the girls have reached a crossroads!<br />
As protests erupt in the street</p>

<p>Ghouls prowl our neighborhoods, trying to look tough<br />
Looking for the scary brown men<br />
Or anyone close enough</p>

<p>Fires rage in the city of angels<br />
For the second time this year<br />
The media is taking all kinds of weird angles<br />
Should probably stick to the blogosphere</p>

<p>More blood for the Blood God<br />
Lights, camera, bitch, smile<br />
I’ll wait for you to applaud<br />
As the chain gang marches single file</p>

<p>Another casualty<br />
Time for another meme<br />
We treat everything so casually<br />
You can watch it all on a live stream</p>

<p>Blood on the pavement<br />
Gas in the air<br />
Mass displacement<br />
It’s fucking everywhere</p>

<p>Dreams soured<br />
Everything is in decline<br />
Feeling like a coward<br />
Six thousand miles away from the front line.</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo by Nijwam Swargiary on Unsplash]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Humbly, I kneel before your altar.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/humbly-i-kneel-before-your-altar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Humbly, I kneel before your altar." /><published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/humbly-i-kneel-before-your-altar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/humbly-i-kneel-before-your-altar/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1727448826555-de5a31dc675a?q=80&amp;w=2340&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D" alt="portrait of woman in art gallery" /></p>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@nescafe_kun">Moutaman Kamal</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/a-couple-of-people-standing-in-front-of-a-picture--nkQ3RjLa0E">Unsplash</a></div>

<p>As the sun rises, so do I.<br />
Tired and weary, I drag myself to the altar<br />
hoping to meet my muse.<br />
Some days they readily greet me.<br />
Others, they are silent and unseen.</p>

<p>In her absence, I look elsewhere<br />
to false idols.<br />
Thinking, <em>that could be me</em>.<br />
But I’m left wanting,<br />
insufficient, always inadequate;<br />
never enough.</p>

<p>I should know better.<br />
Many a Sunday I heard the tale of the irreverent Nebuchadnezzar,<br />
his blasphemy an allegory<br />
for the pitfalls of a false ideology.</p>

<p>But what else am I to do when left to my own devices?</p>

<p>In these moments, disturbing thoughts obscure my vision.<br />
Hypotheticals, as my mind is wont to do.</p>

<p>What if this is it?<br />
What if this is all there is?<br />
What if this is all I am?<br />
Could I accept that?</p>

<p>I don’t think so.<br />
I have to be more.</p>

<p>O Lord, I don’t know who I am anymore.<br />
Once upon a time, I had a clear vision of who I thought I was<br />
but I fear it was merely a fantasy.</p>

<p>Am I a boy?<br />
Surely not!<br />
Am I a girl?<br />
Next question.</p>

<p>To love me is to undergo an overwhelming metamorphosis.<br />
Bravery and strength —<br />
these things demanded of me, yet I am wholly lacking.</p>

<p>I am not strong<br />
and I am not brave.<br />
I am fucking terrified.</p>

<p>I am nothing but meek and small<br />
despite my above-average frame,<br />
a cruel joke from an even crueler creator.</p>

<p>If I kneel at your altar and clasp my hands,<br />
will you light the way?</p>

<p>If I bow my head and surrender my worries,<br />
will you teach me the truth?</p>

<p>If I confess my sins and expel jealously from my heart,<br />
will you breathe life into this flesh?</p>

<p>I feel weaker than I’ve ever been,<br />
unsure if I can bear this weight until its destination.<br />
Sometimes I wish I could go back to the way things used to be —<br />
everything was simpler then.</p>

<p>But this I know to be true:<br />
willful ignorance may have been easy,<br />
but it was a product of the serpent’s conniving tongue.<br />
Nothing but Death awaited in that place.</p>

<p>Enshrouded in a thick gloom,<br />
faith is difficult to sustain.<br />
At times, it’s all I can do to stop myself from screaming.</p>

<p>Then I think about your teachings<br />
your awesome image<br />
your warm bosom —<br />
to be in your charge is to be loved<br />
and realize this has all been worth it.</p>

<p>In you, I entrust my everything.</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="trans" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo by Moutaman Kamal on Unsplash]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">38,880,000 seconds and counting.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/38880000-seconds-and-counting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="38,880,000 seconds and counting." /><published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/38880000-seconds-and-counting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/38880000-seconds-and-counting/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1551892644-51a6e2e8fc65?q=80&amp;w=994&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D" alt="taper candle on cupcake" /></p>
<div class="caption">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@angelekamp">Angèle Kamp</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/taper-candle-on-cupcake-poH6OvcEeXE">Unsplash</a></div>

<p>Today is your birthday,<br />
although I will make no calls,<br />
send no texts,<br />
offer no gifts.</p>

<p>I’d like to,<br />
but we don’t talk anymore.</p>

<p>It’s been 450 days<br />
or 10,800 hours<br />
or 648,000 minutes<br />
since we last spoke.</p>

<p>I can’t pretend to understand what happened.</p>

<p>Was it something I said?<br />
Did I miss a critical social cue?<br />
Did I do something to offend you?</p>

<p>Or was it simply time for us to end?</p>

<p>I still think back to the time we spent together:<br />
the late night phone calls,<br />
the conversations about boys,<br />
the aimless strolls through the woods<br />
where the alligator lady dwelt.</p>

<p>I still think back to photosynthesis.</p>

<p>Of course,<br />
there were the arguments,<br />
and the bickering,<br />
and the accusations,<br />
and …</p>

<p>I cannot deny these past 450 days have been less complicated,<br />
less stressful,<br />
generally easier<br />
as result of your absence.</p>

<p>And yet, they’ve been all the more lonely.</p>

<p>Times are scary;<br />
are you well?<br />
We left off on a cliffhanger;<br />
are you married now?<br />
Did you finally get your own place?</p>

<p>Are you happy?<br />
I hope so.</p>

<p>I really do.</p>

<p>In our last conversation<br />
you lamented that I never seemed happy.<br />
But look at me now!<br />
I wish you were here to meet me —<br />
the real me.</p>

<p>You never had a chance to meet Sage,<br />
and that’s a shame.<br />
(for both of us)<br />
I think you would’ve liked her.</p>

<p>But maybe our separation was necessary for us to grow.<br />
Maybe we needed to shed the past<br />
to move forward in the present;<br />
maybe we were just collateral.</p>

<p>I wish things ended differently.<br />
I wish they never ended at all,<br />
but I would’ve settled<br />
for ending things on an amicable note.</p>

<p>Despite the biting words,<br />
the hurt feelings,<br />
the hole left in your wake;<br />
despite everything,<br />
I wish you well.</p>

<p>Happy birthday.</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Photo by Angèle Kamp on Unsplash]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The mountains are beautiful this time of year.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/the-mountains-are-beautiful-this-time-of-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The mountains are beautiful this time of year." /><published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/the-mountains-are-beautiful-this-time-of-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/the-mountains-are-beautiful-this-time-of-year/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/images/loose/mountains.jpg" alt="a grassy field with mountains in the background" /></p>
<div class="caption">Somewhere, Nowhere, Japan</div>

<p>Spring has arrived and so have the birds,<br />
and the bees,<br />
and the flowers,<br />
and even the weeds.</p>

<p>Spring has arrived but my chest has not.<br />
Nor my hips,<br />
my posterior,<br />
or my libido.</p>

<p>Yes, spring has arrived but still She eludes me.</p>

<p>The mountains are beautiful this time of year.<br />
Towering high above our abode,<br />
keeping watch<br />
ever vigilantly.</p>

<p>If I had a million dollars, I’d quit my job<br />
and trek to one of their peaks.<br />
Seclude myself away while I grow,<br />
change,<br />
metamorphose.</p>

<p>If only for a few years, I’d like to live upon them.<br />
Away from all the people —<br />
enough time for everyone to forget Him;<br />
enough time for me to know to Her.</p>

<p>The mountains are beautiful this time of year.<br />
The clouds hang above so peacefully,<br />
gently drifting in the breeze,<br />
carefree.</p>

<p>I’d like to soar alongside them —<br />
high, high above.<br />
To spare myself the awkward moments,<br />
embarrassing encounters,<br />
and dirty looks.</p>

<p>To watch from above how to be a woman.<br />
To learn how to move,<br />
how to speak;<br />
how to be the person that I am,<br />
instead of the person I’m not.</p>

<p>The mountains are beautiful this time of year.<br />
Their slopes dotted with bristly trees,<br />
forever bathed in a deep shade.</p>

<p>So, too, is my face —<br />
veiled in an ever-present five o’clock shadow.<br />
But unlike the mountains,<br />
it is not pretty on me.</p>

<p>It is ugly and heinous.<br />
A reminder of this obscene birthright forced upon me.<br />
My captor —<br />
this body.<br />
It refuses to let go.</p>

<p>The mountains are beautiful this time of year, aren’t they?<br />
Their cerulean and verdant hues like brushstrokes<br />
from an unseen colossal artist.</p>

<p>I think of them as I paint in the mirror each morning.<br />
But I never turn out quite so beautiful<br />
as the mountains above.</p>

<p>I am enveloped in beauty,<br />
immersed in rich scenery.<br />
Yet so devoid of it in myself.</p>

<p>I’m trying.<br />
O, god, I’m trying!<br />
I’m doing my damnedest,<br />
but it feels like it isn’t enough.</p>

<p>The mountains are beautiful this time of year,<br />
and they intimidate me.</p>

<p>Will I ever compare?<br />
Could I ever harness their beauty?<br />
Is it conceited to desire such things?<br />
Do these musings make me a lesser person?</p>

<p>Indeed, the mountains are so beautiful this time of year.<br />
And I know you’re beautiful, too.<br />
Sometimes I catch glimpses of you.<br />
A trick of the light?<br />
Maybe,<br />
I’m delusional,<br />
or maybe,<br />
I’ve finally started to piece together who I really am;<br />
who you are —<br />
who We are.</p>

<p>I can’t wait to finally meet you<br />
in full,<br />
but I wish it could be under different circumstances.<br />
Simpler times.<br />
Safer times.<br />
I wish this could be our little secret —<br />
just you and me.<br />
With all the time in the world to ourselves,<br />
until we’re ready to reintegrate into society.</p>

<p>The mountains are so damn beautiful this time of year.<br />
I take them for granted, I know.<br />
I’m so focused on what could be,<br />
or what will be,<br />
or what was,<br />
I forget what is.</p>

<p>Those mountains?<br />
They’ve always been beautiful, truthfully.<br />
Just like you.<br />
You’ve always been there, just under the surface;<br />
waiting,<br />
waiting<br />
so patiently.</p>

<p>Thank you<br />
for not giving up;<br />
for clinging onto hope<br />
even when I had lost mine many years ago.</p>

<p>I’m here now, 
wrapped in the warm embrace<br />
of those beautiful mountains. ❤️</p>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="trans" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Somewhere, Nowhere, Japan]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Saw the TV Glow and it terrified me.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/i-saw-the-tv-glow-and-it-terrified-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Saw the TV Glow and it terrified me." /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/i-saw-the-tv-glow-and-it-terrified-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/i-saw-the-tv-glow-and-it-terrified-me/"><![CDATA[<div class="fullwidth"><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/hero.jpg" alt="Owen looks at Maddy, who is crying" /></div>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>
<div class="contentWarning"> strong language, anti-LGBTQ+ rhetoric</div>
<div class="spoilerWarning">Vague spoilers for <i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>.</div>
<div class="infoWarning">This is technically an addition to <a href="/2025/so-long-2024-a-media-retrospective/">January’s post</a>. However, this piece stands on its own. Read the prior post first… or don’t!</div>
<hr />
<h2 id="previously-on-the-pink-opaque">Previously on “The Pink Opaque”</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/tvglow.jpg" alt="I Saw the TV Glow movie poster" /></p>
<div class="caption">Jane Schoenbrun (A24), 2024</div>

<p><em>I Saw the TV Glow</em> is a horror film, but not really. There are no monsters, nor any scares. It isn’t gory or especially violent. It’s a horror film, except it isn’t scary.</p>

<p>Well, it isn’t scary in the traditional sense. Taken literally, <em>TV Glow</em> would appear to be a bizarre concoction of nonsensical plot points and bewildering performances. But this isn’t the sort of film one watches while assuming a vegetative state; on the contrary, it’s a film that demands to be <em>read</em>. Within its text lies a poignant allegory for realizing one’s identity and a haunting portent of what happens when one chooses to ignore it.</p>

<p>This film terrified me. It shook me to my core. It was as if I were witnessing a prophecy of my own life play out on the screen. <em>TV Glow</em> looked me in the eye and said, “<em>Don’t look away. This is important. This could be you if you keep down this path.”</em> I didn’t like what I saw, but that was the point.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I know it’s scary. That’s part of it.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I saw myself in Owen’s meekness, his awkward stumbling through life, and his horror at catching glimpses of his true self.</p>

<p>I observed how, like me, Owen’s high school walls formed a prison, yet provided safe haven from home; his home’s walls formed another—different—prison, yet provided safe haven from school. He was stuck in a paradoxical, draining loop that was all-too-familiar: always relieved to leave one’s current locale but always dreading the next, never able to verbalize that uneasiness.</p>

<p>I hung on Maddy’s every word as she <a href="https://youtu.be/sty6mEHLT-A?si=1lxk2pa6Ui8abvu-">waxed poetic in the planetarium</a>. She was talking about <em>me</em>. She was talking <em>to</em> me. And she looked <em>good</em> doing it, too. Confident. Powerful. Things I wasn’t.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/planetarium.jpg" alt="closeup of Maddy in the planetarium" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>I witnessed Owen wither as a result of ignoring Maddy’s pleadings. I watched as his movements slowed to a crawl and his breathing became labored.</p>

<p>Then, a scream.</p>

<p>A cry for help.</p>

<p>Silence.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sorry about that before.<br />
Sorry about before.<br />
Just a new medication I’m on.<br />
Sorry.<br />
I’m sorry about before.<br />
I’m sorry about that before.<br />
Sorry.<br />
I’m sorry.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Cut to black. Roll credits.</p>

<div class="break"><img src="/assets/images/break-beans.png" /></div>

<p>I sat frozen in my seat. Do I cry? Scream? Smile? A million emotions swirled within me, but I didn’t know which I was supposed to be paying attention to. All of them? Just a few? Only one?</p>

<p>I had felt a similar sensation once before. A couple of years ago, when I began to become aware of my Autistic identity, I felt an overwhelming mix of emotions: fear of being labelled Autistic, joy at discovering a key part of myself, sorrow at all the time lost. The feelings I felt in this moment were similar, but one emotion was much more prominent this time: pure, unbridled terror.</p>

<h2 id="act-one-sucking-down-the-luna-juice">Act One: Sucking down the Luna Juice</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/melancholy.jpg" alt="closeup of Mr. Melancholy" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>Sometime during high school, there was a period in which I had difficulty discerning between dream and reality. Each night, I would relive the day I had just experienced but with subtle details changed. I started to reference things that had only existed in my dreams, and people would look at me like I was crazy. Maybe I was. It was a weird time.</p>

<p>Suddenly, one day it all stopped. I was worried for years afterward that the gaslighting dreams would return, but they never did. Now, they remain nothing more than memories themselves.</p>

<p>Were the dreams even real? Or was the entire situation simply a (literal) nightmare? I suppose I wouldn’t know.</p>

<p>Memory is strange, indeed. We tend to afford our memories more credibility than they deserve. Reliance on <a href="https://innocenceproject.org/how-eyewitness-misidentification-can-send-innocent-people-to-prison/">eyewitness accounts has led to many wrongful convictions</a>, for example. Despite decades of science warning against the pitfalls of memory, it’s hard to deny just how <em>damn convincing</em> our memories are. Even when faced with undeniable proof one has falsely remembered something, it can still be difficult to accept.</p>

<p>I distinctly remember being in school during 9/11. My teacher wheeled in a TV—<em>no, it was mounted to the ceiling</em>—turned on Fox News—<em>or was it NBC?</em>—and we watched as the second plane hit—<em>er, we tuned in after both planes had hit.</em> I can clearly picture all of this happening in my fifth grade classroom.</p>

<p>Except, I was three-years-old when 9/11 occurred. Logically, I know this memory is impossible, yet it <em>feels so real</em>.</p>

<p>Recently, I’ve observed how writing shapes my recollection of events. When I explain my experiences with Autism, I usually end up summarizing one of my posts, often using the same verbiage contained within. I am, in a way, altering my memories as I write; creating nicely packaged, polished narratives that only include the details I deem relevant or important at the time of writing.</p>

<p>But what if I miss something significant? As before, I suppose I wouldn’t know if I did.</p>

<p>While <em>TV Glow</em> was what directly led me to come to terms with my transgender self, there have been <em>so</em> many signs pointing toward my true self for years. I find it regrettable that I finally admitted I’m trans at the ripe old age of 27 because those were 27 years in which I’d lived in a way that was toxic to me. But of course, we can’t change the past.</p>

<p>However, we <em>can</em> change our recollection of the past—and I did just that. Much of the following I had completely forgotten until I put pen to paper for this piece. On one hand, it’s validating realizing the feelings I’m experiencing aren’t actually anything new because I’ve always been trans. On the other hand, it’s terrifying how things so vital to who I am were so easily forgotten.</p>

<p>At least I can take solace in having rediscovered these memories.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Do you ever feel like you’re narrating your own life, watching it play in front of you like an episode of television?<br />
Or do you ever have a hard time distinguishing between what happened in the show and what happened in real life?<br />
Like somehow the memories got jumbled around?</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="righteous-immorality">Righteous immorality</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/parachute.jpg" alt="young Owen under gym parachute in trans flag colors" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>I grew up as a pastor’s kid in southern Texas, where there was a church on every corner. I remember sitting in a church sanctuary on the Sunday after the Supreme Court ruled gay marriage legal nationwide. A video from the Southern Baptist Convention showed a man standing in front of the Capitol building, with the American flag carefully kept in frame. He decried the Supreme Court’s ruling, whined about the “war” on Christian values, and ended with a message of—what I assume was meant to elicit—hope: “We may have lost the battle, but the war isn’t over.”</p>

<p>A somber air loomed in the church that day. It was bewildering: We had all just lived through one of the greatest advancements in American human rights that had occurred in my lifetime, but we were all sat there as if some horrible travesty had just occurred.</p>

<p>Until <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2015/11/03/houston-anti-discrimination-ordinance-early-voting/">Houston’s “bathroom ordinance</a>,” an anti-discrimination bill aimed at serving the LGBTQ+ community that was rejected by over 60% of voters in 2015, I was wholly unaware of the existence of transgender people. In those days—and by “those days” I mean only a decade ago—the church had its sights set on abortion and the first three letters of LGBT. Once conservative Christianity handily lost its fight against gay marriage, it shifted its sights toward the (next) biggest threat facing our children: the <em>trans agenda</em>.</p>

<p>And there I was thinking guns and mental health issues posed the largest risks to our children’s safety. <em>What a fool I was!</em></p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D7thOvSvC4E?si=TXlM0xkfesSl1PS5" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
<div class="caption">Anti-trans political ads like this one were my introduction to trans people. I don’t recall a single person around me taking issue with this sort of language being used to describe a group of human beings. Casual transphobia was just that—casual. No one thought anything of it.</div>

<p>Having grown up in that world, it feels <em>personal</em> seeing it at the forefront of today’s fascism. Those leading the charge against trans rights are just the sort of people I grew up around. Yet, I can’t say I am surprised. Every Sunday, I was told how important acceptance and forgiveness were, but I failed to ever observe those values in practice within the church.</p>

<p>After I left my hometown, I began to find myself around queer people, and among them I found the acceptance and forgiveness the church had preached about actually put into practice. <em>Hmm.</em></p>

<p>Despite the Bible seemingly suggesting that all sin is more or less equal,<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> and witnessing many a sermon about how all sin is equal in the eyes of God, it was quite apparent that there was a “special” place carved out for <em>the homosexuals</em> (and by extension, <em>those transgenders</em>).</p>

<p>Steal something? Cheat on your wife? Murder someone? Don’t worry, “for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.”<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> But <em>homosexuality</em>? Sure, we’ve all sinned, but <em>not like that!</em></p>

<p>There were multiple things that pushed me to leave the faith, but a prominent issue for me was the church’s views on homosexuality. While I didn’t see myself as gay, I didn’t see any reason for not accepting people who were. Whenever I asked what was wrong with being gay, I was never given an actual answer. Instead, I got various forms of: <em>“Well, because the Bible says so.” “God intended for men to be with women.” “It’s an abomination.”</em> Of course, none of those answers were justifiable reasons for rejecting an entire group of people. It was bigotry, plain and simple. What I found especially shocking was how little effort was put forth to hide that fact.</p>

<p>The church’s influence extended far past its four walls: When I finally left Christianity in (a public) high school, I was taken aback by my classmates’ reactions. Many of them whom I’d never heard mention things like “God” or “Jesus” told me how stupid I was for not believing in God. Being Christian was the only acceptable state of being. If one wasn’t Christian, well, <em>what’s wrong with you?</em></p>

<h3 id="some-kids-were-stuffed-in-lockers-i-was-stuffed-in-a-closet">Some kids were stuffed in lockers, I was stuffed in a closet</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/fireside.jpg" alt="Owen in front of a campfire" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>In high school, I wore skinny jeans and crossed my legs. I had a set of glittery binders in bright colors. I was friends with girls and we’d lament how it wasn’t fair that I was a boy and so we couldn’t do all the things other friends could, like have sleepovers. I had long-ish hair, and moved and spoke in ways my classmates considered <em>like a girl</em>.</p>

<p>It was the early 2010s, so of course my sexuality was a frequent topic of discussion. For a time, I thought maybe my classmates had a point, at least partially. There was no doubt in my mind that I liked girls, but maybe I liked boys, too? I considered it, but concluded that I <em>probably</em> didn’t like boys in that way. I was just a little… different.</p>

<p>“Are you gay?” they’d ask with a frown. “No, I’m <em>metrosexual</em>,” I’d explain.</p>

<p>“Glittery binders? What are you, <em>fucking gay</em>?” they’d mock. “Just <em>fruity</em>,” I’d deflect.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup></p>

<p>I wasn’t offended at the notion of being gay, but I realized even then that my classmates weren’t <em>really</em> interested in my sexuality. They were trying to determine whether I was worthy of respect; whether I held any value. And so, when I made claims like, “I’m in touch with my feminine side,” I was really making thinly veiled attempts at justifying my existence to my peers.</p>

<p>Even outside of school, I wasn’t exempt from such derision. While out shopping for shoes before the new school year, I wanted to buy pink shoelaces. My father pulled me aside and spat, “Son, are you <em>gay</em>?” The way he spoke the word “gay”—it was as if he had just tasted something foul.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/gayParentsMessageCap.jpg" alt="iMessage messages that read: &quot;AHEM They said your jeans make you look a little gay&quot; &quot;Just a little&quot;" /></p>
<div class="caption">The first time I met my high school girlfriend’s parents, they assumed I was gay and called me a “faggot” after I left.</div>

<p>At school, all the boys ever talked about was who and what was gay, and <em>pussy</em>:</p>

<p><em>“Bro, I think I’m gonna get some pussy this weekend.”</em></p>

<p><em>“You know what your problem is, bro? You need some fuckin’ pussy, man.”</em></p>

<p><em>“Bro, I fucked so-and-so last night. Her pussy was so tight!”</em></p>

<p>The crudeness of their talk always disgusted me. To them, women weren’t much different than cold cuts at the deli counter. They might try to write it off as “locker room talk” now, but I saw the truth in their words. I wouldn’t trust any of them alone in a room with a woman. Presumably many of the girls at school also felt this way because very few of the boys frothing about <em>pussy</em> ad nauseam rarely—if ever—“scored,” as they’d put it. I hope for everyone’s sake that they’ve grown up since then, but I have my doubts. Many of them are likely parading about in bright red hats, strapping nine-millimeters to their waists, whinging about men’s rights, and flying flags off the backs of their irresponsibly oversized pick-up trucks with <em>MAGA</em> bumper stickers plastered over their tailgates. <em>You know, the image of peak masculinity.</em><sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup></p>

<p>I digress, but the crude nature of the boys’ talk always felt somehow personal. The targets of their vulgarity were my friends—my <em>real</em> friends. The ones I related to, the ones I felt comfortable around—the girl-friends. Further, the boys’ coarse remarks carried a not-so-subtle undertone: a full-blown rejection of things like <em>feelings</em> and <em>vulnerability</em> and <em>self-expression</em>—things I was well-acquainted with. Not only was I “gay,” I was also a “<em>pussy</em>.” The only way I could’ve sunk further on the social ladder was if everyone had learned I am Autistic.</p>

<p>I wish I could state that I called out my classmates’ toxicity when it arose, but to do so would be deceitful. I nodded along and acted like it was okay. I laughed at their misogynistic jokes, as if I were <em>one of the boys!</em> In time, I started to act like them.</p>

<p>I regret that now, but I can’t blame myself. I was just trying to fit in. Just trying to survive. As the years passed, and I continued to be told what it meant to be a man—the <em>thing</em> that everyone referred to me as—I grew increasingly confused: <em>Is this what I’m supposed to be? Is this what I am?</em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/2015imNotGayMessageCap.png" alt="iMessage messages that read: &quot;You'd be forgiven if you thought I was gay&quot; &quot;Yup I'm quite different&quot; &quot;For the better I might add&quot; grimacing emoji &quot;I was just really weird in general, and I look back at the stuff I would do or say or whatever and it's just so cringey&quot;" /></p>
<div class="caption">2015: Explaining my “embarrassing” former self.</div>

<p>By the time I graduated, I wore straight-cut jeans and lugged around a dull black binder. I cut my hair short and stopped crossing my legs. It was time to grow up, stop fucking around, and act like a <em>man</em>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sorry about that before.<br />
Sorry about before.<br />
Sorry.<br />
I’m sorry.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="soft-boiled">Soft-boiled</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/gravewalk.jpg" alt="Owen and Maddy walking on a football field" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>Early in university, I wrote a piece for the student newspaper about how I resented being mocked for liking the color pink, among other things. It opened with the following:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I don’t make a very good man. Before anyone asks, no, I’m not coming out as a woman or anything along those lines.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Oh, the irony…</p>

<p>I wrote a great many things for that newspaper, most of which I do not remember. The things that I do recall writing are the pieces that I was either exceptionally proud of or generated a bit of controversy.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup> The aforementioned column fits neither of these categories, however. I remember it only because of the intense shame I felt immediately after sending it off to my editor.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’m not macho, I don’t have very many guy friends, and I wear my heart on my sleeve. I must be gay or something, right?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I felt embarrassed. I had written the forbidden words. <em>Why the fuck did I write that?</em> I couldn’t enter the newsroom for several weeks afterward, lest I had to look anyone in the eye. That shame stuck with me throughout the rest of my time at university.</p>

<p>At the end of that piece, I wrote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What I’ve always found rather amusing is we are often told to be ourselves in pop culture. Really, what that means is to be ourselves within the boundaries of acceptable behavior as defined by society. How shameful.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>These words are the clear product of repression. I was <em>so</em> close, yet it wouldn’t be until almost a decade later that I would finally put the pieces together.</p>

<h2 id="act-two-into-the-frying-pan">Act Two: Into the frying pan</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/pinkGlow.jpg" alt="Owen and Maddy in profile, bathed in pink light" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>Coming out as Autistic was scary, but at the same time it was something that everyone around me already knew, even if they didn’t realize it. <em>Sage is a little socially awkward</em>, they’d think. <em>Sage is eccentric</em>. And when I did unveil that I am Autistic, it was rather anticlimactic. Ultimately, “Autism” means very little to most people. “You’re Autistic? Alright,” they said, shrugging their shoulders.</p>

<p>Coming out as trans is different. People have <em>opinions</em> on what “trans” means. To some, it is merely a term that refers to those whose assigned gender does not match their identity; to others, it is a term indicative <em>of</em> identity and a greater community; to others still, it is a term that refers to predators. Trans hate is so prevalent at the moment that it is a prominent feature of the current U.S. administration.</p>
<div class="sidebar">
<h3>The new morning groove</h3>

It’s become something of a ritual of mine to wake up, grab a coffee, and peruse my home country’s latest efforts to erase my existence.
<ul>
	<li><b>January 20</b>: Trump takes office and signs an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/">executive order</a> that declares that the federal government will henceforth recognize only two sexes.</li>
	<li><b>January 27</b>: Trump signs another <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/prioritizing-military-excellence-and-readiness/">executive order</a> targeting transgender people in the military, citing “adoption of a gender identity inconsistent with an individual’s sex conflicts with a soldier’s commitment to an honorable, truthful, and disciplined lifestyle, even in one’s personal life.”</li>
	<li><b>January 28</b>: <i>Guess what, motherfucker??</i> Trump signs yet another <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/protecting-children-from-chemical-and-surgical-mutilation/">executive order</a>, this time attacking gender-affirming care for trans youth (defined as those 19 and below), reasoning it is “chemical and surgical mutilation.” <i>Won’t someone think of the children?!</i></li>
	<li><b>February</b>: The great information purge begins. Government, healthcare providers’, and nonprofits’ websites have large swaths of information deleted from their pages. The <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/state-department-travel-safety-website">State Department’s travel safety site</a> has all references to, and specific information pertaining to, transgender people on its LGBT page removed—now titled “LGB Travelers.” The National Park Service’s page on the Stonewall Monument <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/protests-erupt-at-stonewall-after">follows suit</a>, among many others.</li>
	<li><b>February 5</b>: <i>I’m tired, y’all.</i> Trump signs—<i>can you guess?</i>—an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/keeping-men-out-of-womens-sports/">executive order</a> with a title that says it all: “Keeping Men Out of Women’s Sports.” The <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/06/ncaa-ban-transgender-athletes">NCAA kisses the royal orange ass</a> a day later.</li>
	<li><b>February 18</b>: The <a href="https://news.bgov.com/bloomberg-government-news/trumps-dhs-loosens-sexual-orientation-based-surveillance-policy">Department of Homeland Security removes limitations</a> on surveilling individuals based on gender identity or sexual orientation, effectively allowing mass-surveillance of the LGBTQ+ community. <i>This seems… bad.</i></li>
	<li><b>February 24</b>: An internal memo details policy changes on issuing visas, in response to February 5’s executive order. This has the potential to <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/marco-rubio-may-have-just-banned?r=21qo2w&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;showWelcomeOnShare=false">affect all incoming foreign trans people</a>.</li>
</ul>
This list is far from comprehensive, by the way.
<img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/badPlace.jpg" alt="Kristen Bell saying, 'This is The Bad Place.'" />
<div class="caption"><i>The Good Place</i>, NBC</div>
It is vital to understand the grave danger these attacks pose to all of us. History shows that <i>bad things</i> follow the dehumanization of marginalized groups, and “dehumanization” is <i>exactly</i> what these policies are attempting to do. Eliminating our legal statuses, restricting our movement, altering records and resources to remove any reference to us—this goes much further than a simple political, social, moral, or religious disagreement. These are the sorts of things that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ten_stages_of_genocide">precede the worst kinds of events</a>.
If we continue on this current trajectory, very bad things <i>will</i> happen. It’s not a possibility. It’s a certainty. It’s just a matter of <i>when</i>.
<br /><br />
And when they’re through with us? Will their thirst for blood be satiated? Well, history tells us a thing or two about that, as well.

<div class="substack-post-embed"><p lang="en">Nazis Burned Trans Books To Usher In Fascism: Now Trump Does The Same by Erin Reed</p><p>Transgender people have often been a canary in the coalmines of Democracy.</p><a data-post-link="" href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/nazis-burned-trans-books-to-usher">Read on Substack</a></div><script async="" src="https://substack.com/embedjs/embed.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

Since I moved to Japan, I’ve had an ongoing internal debate on returning to America. I always assumed I <i>would</i> return; it was just a question of <i>when</i>. Well, that debate has swiftly been put to rest. I no longer feel safe in my home country, and I have no idea when it will be safe for me to return, even for a brief visit.
<br /><br />
Still, I’m extremely fortunate that I live in a country where I <i>do</i> feel safe. Many are not so lucky.
</div>
<p>It’s a less-than-ideal time to be doing this, to put it lightly. This is certainly not the sort of atmosphere anyone wants to come out in, but it’s the one I’ve got. I’m not scared of being trans, but I am scared of what it means within the culture we currently find ourselves in.</p>

<p>I’m fearful of the kind of repercussions words like these could bring in the coming years, let alone in the current moment. I’m afraid that visiting my family in Texas is no longer safe for me—if I even have a family to visit, once I divulge all of this to them.</p>

<p>It’s scary, but I can’t deny that the purple-pink girlypop glow of “The Pink Opaque” calls to me. Once one has the realization of who they really are—that “egg crack” moment—it marks a point of no return. What was once a confusing whirlwind of emotions becomes an undeniable picture of one’s true identity, and one can either obey its call or wither away like Owen. There’s hardly a choice to be made.</p>

<p>I already knew the truth of my identity long before I ever sat down to watch <em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>. I’ve known for a very long time that something was wrong—the way I’ve been living is wrong. I thought I’d found the explanation for those feelings last year in Autism, but it turned out that was only half of the answer. The other half I had known for most of my life, but had chosen to ignore it.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I told myself,<br />
“This isn’t normal. This isn’t normal.”<br />
This isn’t how life is supposed to be.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I knew the truth in high school, but it was beaten out of me. I swore to forget these feelings. I told myself it was just a phase. <em>I’m a man! I was just confused.</em></p>

<p>As I entered adulthood, I watched as my physical features grew more and more masculine. As I peered into the mirror every morning, I began to focus on the microscale: on my scalp as I did my hair, on my cheek as I shaved it—never taking in my whole self, for to do so would be to confront the dysphoria at the <em>thing</em> that stared back at me in the mirror.</p>

<p>That dysphoria was a strange experience. I would go weeks, even months, without ever looking at myself properly in the mirror, until one day I would let my guard down and accidentally see myself in full. It was always genuinely shocking. <em>Who the fuck is that?</em></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/genderSwapMessageCap.png" alt="iMessage messages that read: &quot;If only we could swap genders&quot; &quot;haha, yeah if only..&quot;" /></p>
<div class="caption">July 2023</div>

<p>In my mind, when I imagined myself in certain situations—say, in a relationship—I pictured myself as a woman. For years, I never even realized this. I just did it without thinking.</p>

<p>I’ve always felt a disconnect within myself. My mind and body have never been one; they have always been two separate entities. I give commands to this meat-sack that others view as “Sage,” but this awkward, ugly flesh isn’t <em>me</em>. I don’t know <em>what</em> or <em>whose</em> it is, but it isn’t me or mine.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, I’ve chosen for years on end to push these feelings aside. I’ve told myself that everyone feels this way, and in a sense, everyone <em>does</em> feel this way—even the most beautiful of us struggle with self-image. But this goes further than that. This is something more, and I’ve known that for a long time, but I swore to myself that it wasn’t true.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Maddy’s story was insane.<br />
It couldn’t be true.<br />
But some nights … I found myself wondering:<br />
What if she was right?<br />
What if she had been telling the truth?<br />
What if I really was someone else?<br />
Someone beautiful and powerful.<br />
Someone buried alive and suffocating to death.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Eventually, I admitted to a therapist that if I could press a button and immediately become a woman, I’d do so without hesitation. “But that’s just hypothetical,” I hand-waved. “I wouldn’t ever want to actually transition!”</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>That’s just fantasy.<br />
Kid’s stuff.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Yet, the evidence stacked higher and higher. As I researched my neurodivergence and discovered a <a href="https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/transgender-and-gender-diverse-individuals-are-more-likely-to-be-autistic-and-report-higher-autistic">higher proportion of transgender people among the Autistic population</a>, I told myself I wasn’t a part of those statistics. When I caught myself staring at women, I told myself it was merely out of lust—I didn’t want to <em>be</em> them! When I felt things stirring deep inside of me whenever other queer people would share their experiences, I told myself I was being <em>too</em> empathetic. <em>I told myself I wasn’t trans.</em></p>

<p><em>You’re a man.</em></p>

<p><em>You’re a man.</em></p>

<p><em>Be a fucking man!</em></p>

<p>But the heart wants what the heart wants. Despite my best efforts at repressing these feelings, they refuse to be silenced. Sometimes my hair falls into place, my skin glows, the light bounces off my lips just right, and for a brief moment I’m able to look at myself—<em>my whole self</em>—and feel as if I am approaching “pretty.” As I type this, I look down at the keyboard to see my painted nails, their gloss reflecting the fluorescent lights above, and the euphoria they spur is undeniable.</p>

<p><em>You’re not a man.</em></p>

<p><em>You’re not a man.</em></p>

<p><em>You’re not a fucking man!</em></p>

<p>I’ve been running from myself for my entire life. Maddy forced me to confront who I really am, and realize that I’m sick of running. I can’t do it anymore. I won’t.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I knew I needed to come back and save you.<br />
So that the show can continue.<br />
So that we can get to season six.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="act-three-rebirth">Act Three: Rebirth</h2>
<h3 id="new-hemisphere-new-me">New hemisphere, new me</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/football.jpg" alt="Maddy with Owen in a dress, facing away from the camera, and Mr. Melancholy in the sky" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>Japan represented a fresh start: I was moving to a new country on the other side of the world in which no one knew who I was. It was the perfect opportunity to change my name.</p>

<p>Thus, Sage was born. And with their birth came a newfound sense of self: Sage offered me full permission to be whomever I wanted, without the weight of others’ expectations. Years of people pleasing had left me as a shell of a person. I had no identity; I didn’t really exist. I was merely whomever everyone else wanted me to be. Whomever they told me to be. Obedient and without agency. Sage lifted me from those tired shackles and dared me to be an actual person. <em>You deserve a voice. You are allowed to exist.</em></p>

<p>A couple of years later, they dared me to push further: I moved away from overtly masculine-leaning attire. I grew my hair out longer than I had ever done before. It felt right.</p>

<p>I painted my nails. I had always wanted to do so, but I was too fearful of other’s reactions. However, when I finally decided to go for it, it felt <em>so</em> right—as if it were always supposed to be this way.</p>

<p>In the wake of that euphoria, it became clear that it was time to fully embrace my trans self. I found a clinic that offered HRT and scheduled an appointment.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup></p>

<p>It was time to leave the Midnight Realm once and for all.</p>

<h3 id="the-magic-potion-the-slaying-of-a-great-beast-and-the-burger-council">The magic potion, the slaying of a great beast, and the Burger Council</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/headTouch.jpg" alt="Tara and Isabel resting their heads on each other, Pink Opaque ghost tattoos visible" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>The elevator doors opened and I was spit out into a small carpeted space with shoes lined up along the walls. I removed my shoes, changed into a pair of slippers, and entered the clinic’s lobby. It was quiet and inviting, with wooden floors and wall paneling. Plants were stationed in the corners of the room and the waiting area featured private cubicle-like seating.</p>

<p>I approached the front desk and informed the receptionist that I had an appointment. They nodded and motioned for me to sit. I found a seat with a window overlooking the street below, and watched pedestrians saunter by: masculine, feminine, androgynous; tall, short; thin, wide; Japanese, foreign; short-haired, long-haired; young, old. <em>All these people living their lives, while I’m about to start a new one…</em></p>

<p>A door cracked open behind me and a man’s face popped out from behind it. “Sage-san,” it called. “<em>Hai</em>,” I replied. The face disappeared and I entered the room after it. I was expecting a formal examination room, but evidently this was the doctor’s personal office. To the left, a large desk sat against a window and atop it laid a mess of books, binders, papers, and computer screens. Behind the desk lurked a copy machine, and on the far wall stood shelves with yet more books and binders. It was all rather chaotic, but there seemed to be a method to the madness.</p>

<p>The doctor was seated at the desk, dressed in casual wear. I planted myself on a stool in front of him. Without looking up from the computer screens, he asked, “So, you’re here for female hormones, correct?”</p>

<p>“Yes, that’s right.”</p>

<p>“Can you tell me why?”</p>

<p>I gave my reasoning and he rapped away on a keyboard.</p>

<p>“Is this your first time with hormone therapy?” he asked.</p>

<p>I nodded.</p>

<p>“I see here that you live in another prefecture, so you can’t come in every week for your injection. Are you okay with self-injection?”</p>

<p>“Yes, that’s totally fine.”</p>

<p>“Okay, today I will show you how to do the injection,” he said. “I will also send you video instructions, so please refer to them for your injection next week.”</p>

<p>He left the room and returned a moment later with a small, clear-plastic package in hand. Opening it, he laid its contents out on the desk: a glass vial, a syringe, a pair of needles, an alcoholic wipe, and a bandage. My heart started pounding. <em>This is it.</em></p>

<p>The doctor raised the vial in the air, like it were a precious gemstone. A clear, viscous liquid rested inside. “This is estrogen,” he stated.</p>

<p>For a moment, I thought I saw the glass shine and glimmer, like in a cartoon. <em>Ding!</em></p>

<p>I observed the doctor attach a long needle to the syringe and fill its chamber with the vial’s fluid. Then, he swapped to a short needle and instructed me to expose my stomach. “You inject about two fingers’ width away from your belly button,” he explained. “Ready?”</p>

<p>It was time. I was seconds away from receiving my first dose of estrogen, thereby starting my transition in full. After this, nothing would be quite the same.</p>

<p>Despite having the option to do everything online, I had come two hours away because I wanted to give this moment the appropriate weight it commanded in my mind. Yet, I didn’t feel elated as I had imagined I would. Instead, my stomach twisted into knots. My heart beat even faster and my breathing hastened. <em>Am I sure about this?</em></p>

<p><em>Of course</em>, I was sure about it. There was no doubt in my mind that I wanted the stuff in that syringe, but in that moment I was faced with the sudden realization that <em>all of this</em>—being trans—was no longer limited to the confines of my mind. I couldn’t hide these things anymore. It wasn’t fantasy. It was real, and it was happening <em>right now</em>. While that was incredibly exciting, it also meant that soon I would be faced with the negatives of being visibly trans. It was bittersweet.</p>

<p>I felt a slight prick and watched as the needle sank into my skin.</p>

<p>“Does it hurt?”</p>

<p>I shook my head. “No.”</p>

<p>“It takes some time to inject because of the thick oils.”</p>

<p>I watched as the syringe’s plunger creeped closer to my stomach. Slowly, slowly…</p>

<p>A few seconds later, the syringe was removed and a bandage was placed over the injection site. I was given a few more doses of estrogen to take home <em>and then it was over</em>. The appointment took all of 10 minutes. It was the easiest doctor’s appointment of my life.</p>

<p>It almost felt <em>too</em> easy. It didn’t feel like a big deal at all. It felt mundane. Routine. Unremarkable. <em>Normal</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/postExpectations-messageCap.png" alt="iMessage messages that read: &quot;if the world isn't suddenly tinted in pink blue and white, i'm going to be disappointed&quot; &quot;i better be walkin out that clinic with big tiddies&quot;" /></p>
<div class="caption">Messaging a friend about my HRT appointment.</div>

<p>As I left the clinic, I considered whether I felt any different. I could feel a very slight soreness around the area of the injection, but otherwise I felt exactly as I did just 30 minutes prior. I knew HRT operated on a timescale of months and years, not hours—and certainly not minutes—but I couldn’t help but feel a <em>little</em> disappointed.</p>

<p>The slurry of emotions was confusing and exhausting. Excited, yet scared. Hopeful, yet disappointed. It also happened to be a little after noon, and I hadn’t eaten breakfast that morning. The next course of action was obvious: eat through those feelings.</p>

<p>I marched to a nearby Shake Shack and paid an excessive amount of money for a cheeseburger. It was massive: two soft buns embracing a fat beef patty topped with cheese, lettuce, tomato, “shack sauce,” and a cheese-wrapped fried mushroom that spanned the width of the burger itself—a true American feast. I lifted the thing and felt its immense weight. A mixture of sauce and grease oozed from its backside onto the tray below. I stared at the great beast in my hands for a moment, admiring its splendor; then shifted my gaze toward the black polish on my nails, gleaming under the fluorescent lights above.</p>

<p>There I was about to stuff my face like I was back in America. I had changed a lot, and I was going to change a whole lot more, but I was still <em>me</em>. If anything, I was more <em>me</em> than I’d ever been before.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>And I was me.<br />
I was finally me again.<br />
And it was the season six premiere.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Autistic and now trans—I never expected these to be the defining traits of my time living abroad. Yet, it had all led me here: to an overpriced (yet delicious) burger shop on the opposite side of the globe on which I had spent 90% of my life. Despite everything, I had found my way to one of my oldest guilty pleasures: a <em>disgusting</em>, <em>beautiful</em> burger.</p>

<p>I took a bite, struggling to fit the towering mass in my mouth. Sauce ran down my chin and onto the metal serving tray below, and a medley of umami erupted in my mouth. <em>Oh my god.</em></p>

<p>Ere long, the beast was slain. Nothing remained of it except for a puddle of melted cheese and the grease on my fingers. I sat there in the middle of the restaurant, basking in the afterglow of having conquered the thing.</p>

<p>While I had indulged in greasy food plenty of times in America, the context had always been different. Then, it was a semi-hostile act; an attempt to get “revenge” on the body that I despised. Today was different. The act was the same, but it had shed its malicious undertones.</p>

<p>As I pondered this, a council of disembodied voices gathered in my mind.</p>

<p><em>“Oh, god. Why did we do that?”</em> a shrill voice cried out.</p>

<p>A velvety purr replied, <em>“It was necessary.”</em></p>

<p><em>“Yes, yes!”</em> a reptilian hiss exclaimed. <em>“Necessary! That’s it!”</em></p>

<p><em>“Necessary?”</em> scoffed the first voice. “<em>We feel terrible. Horribly bloated! Why would we ruin such a momentous occasion with an act of self-harm such as this?!”</em></p>

<p>The purr let out a long sigh. <em>“That’s the point! To prove we can still do this.”</em></p>

<p><em>“Do what?”</em> the shrill voice shrieked. <em>“What could we possibly have proven by devouring that… abomination?”</em></p>

<p>The hiss cackled. <em>“That we could! That our appetite is large enough! That we’re good Ameri-”</em></p>

<p><em>“No, you dolt!”</em> spat the purr, its voice cracking. <em>“Yesterday, we dined as a man.</em></p>

<p><em>“Today, we dined as a woman.”</em></p>

<h2 id="next-time-on-the-pink-opaque">Next time on “The Pink Opaque”</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/pinkOpaque.jpg" alt="Tara and Isabel sitting on a dock under a sunset" /></p>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<p>When I imagined transitioning, I pictured bold declarations and sudden results.</p>

<p><em>One day, I wake up and shout, “I’m a woman!” I adopt a new name, start dressing and speaking differently, and I feel</em> all <em>the euphoria. Everyone around me immediately adopts my pronouns. Orchestral music erupts in the streets and depression hurriedly retreats. In a single moment, everything changes.</em></p>

<p>That was a nice fantasy, but of course it wasn’t realistic. In reality, transition is a slow, awkward, and at times painful process.</p>

<p>In some respects, my dysphoria has actually worsened since starting estrogen. Now, I look at myself fully in the mirror every day, on alert for any visible changes. I take a selfie each morning to document my progress and while I’m sure one day I will be glad I did so, this is often a truly torturous task.</p>

<p>I’ve encountered varying degrees of acceptance toward my name and pronouns. It feels <em>great</em> when someone gets them right, and <em>terrible</em> when they don’t.</p>

<p>Currently, my (deep) voice isn’t a major source of dysphoria because it matches the face in the mirror. However, I know there will come a time when that is no longer the case, and it would be ideal to start preparing for that now rather than later. I’ve started dabbling in voice training—yes, I realize “dabbling” isn’t going to cut it—but it is <em>so</em> daunting. Sitting in my apartment doing voice exercises, working on things like <em>pitch</em> and <em>resonance</em> and <em>vocal weight</em>—I know it’s all part of the process, but I feel dumb doing it. Perhaps voice training is more a test of mental fortitude than anything else.</p>

<p>While it’s all a bit awkward and I’d really like for the estrogen to <em>hurry up already</em>, my transition thus far has been <em>overwhelmingly</em> positive. It’s one of the best things that’s ever happened to me, if not <em>the</em> best thing that’s ever happened to me.</p>

<p>I expected estrogen to improve my mental health in a roundabout way. I thought as it altered me to be more in-line with who I envision myself as, my mental health would improve as a result. That’s probably true. However, my mental state did a 180 literally overnight after receiving my first injection. At first, I thought this was simply a result of the knowledge of having started HRT, something I was really excited about. But over a month in, the “novelty” of having started estrogen has waned and I still feel fantastic. It’s not that I’m constantly happy—a certain orange man has seen to it that I’m not—but I’m <em>stable</em>. I can think and process negative thoughts and feelings (like the kind from <a href="/2024/welcome-to-my-water-prison/">rumination</a>, then move on with my day—something I’ve never been able to do. Before estrogen, all it took was one little thing and I would spiral for the rest of the day. No more!</p>

<p>It certainly isn’t visually apparent yet, but I can confirm <em>things are happening</em> in my chest. I noticed toward the end of my second week on estrogen that my chest had become sensitive to touch, which happened far sooner than I ever expected. Any irrational fears I had that I might be immune to estrogen or that I had been given placebo injections were quickly put to rest.</p>

<p>There’s still so much to do. I want to buy new clothes, get my ears pierced, and learn makeup. I also want to legally change my name, although I’m not sure how feasible that is at the moment. Regardless, I can only do so much at a time—capitalism demands its dues, after all.</p>

<p>Transition is a marathon, not a sprint. I remind myself of this while I do my best to simply enjoy the process, instead of focusing solely on the end-goal. I’ll get there eventually, but in the meantime it is enough that I’m seeing actual, tangible results. I’m on the right track.</p>

<p>When I chose a university nine hours away from home, it didn’t lead to happiness like I’d hoped. When I left the country entirely, it also failed to provide the happiness I longed for. Even as I discovered I’m Autistic, for all the good it did and continues to do, I still wasn’t happy.</p>

<p>In embracing my true-self, am I finally happy? I don’t know. I still frequently begin my days ruminating. I still have an array of familial issues. I still grapple with low self-esteem. The problems I had pre-transition are still intact.</p>

<p>And yet, the future has never been brighter. I look forward to tomorrow—an experience I’m wholly unaccustomed to.</p>

<p><a href="https://aridrennen.substack.com/p/how-do-i-know-if-im-transgender">Ari Drennen put it best</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Transitioning did not solve all my problems. Transitioning gave me problems that I consider more interesting, and it made them feel worth solving.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<div class="fullwidth"><img src="/assets/images/tvGlow/thereIsStillTime.jpg" alt="'there is still time' written in chalk" /></div>
<div class="caption"><i>I Saw the TV Glow</i>, A24</div>

<h2 id="addendum-because-this-post-isnt-self-indulgent-enough">Addendum (because this post isn’t self-indulgent enough)</h2>

<p>This month marks one year of <strong>catloaf &amp; coffee</strong>. A year ago, I began processing my Autism diagnosis through the writing I do here. My first post was actually just a private journal entry. I made some changes to accommodate its publication, but 90% of it remains as it was when I wrote it in my journal.</p>

<p>Since then, I no longer keep a journal. I have no need to do so, as this blog has effectively replaced it. It’s an interesting experience writing some of one’s most personal thoughts for the world to see. While not many people actually read the things I write here—honestly, <em>good</em>—there’s always the possibility that anyone <em>could</em> read the things I write, which creates a strange dynamic. Should certain individuals stumble upon this blog, there are some rather awkward situations that could arise. <em>Avert your eyes!</em></p>

<p>Thinking back on that first post: at the time, it felt so <em>daring</em>. So <em>bold</em>. So… <em>risky</em>.</p>

<p>In hindsight, that seems silly. Trivial. Announcing I’m Autistic felt like the biggest thing in the world, but now it’s just a basic fact of life. <em>Yes, I’m Autistic. So what?</em></p>

<p>A year later, and I’m coming out as trans. Once again, this feels <em>daring</em> and <em>bold</em> and <em>risky</em>. However, I’m not so sure that I will find these feelings trivial a year from now. As a trans person, I am detested by many in my home country, among other places. It <em>is</em> risky to come out as trans; I fully expect some not-insignificant fallout involving some family members after I come out to them, for instance.</p>

<p>Maybe it’ll make for a decent blog post, at least.</p>

<p>To date, this post has been the hardest piece for me to write. Not only is it the longest post on <strong>catloaf &amp; coffee</strong> by a significant margin, but it has also taken the longest amount of time to write. I began this piece back in November and planned for its release in December… which became January… which became February… which became March. Originally, I thought I would include this at the end of January’s post because I was apprehensive at the idea of having a standalone “coming out” post. I thought if I were to hide these words at the bottom of a silly post about music, games, and film, it would be “safe.”</p>

<p>Obviously, that didn’t happen because that would’ve been stupid. This thing only works if I’m honest with myself, and by extension, this blog. While on this site I may simply be a name paired with a set of pronouns and a cat emoji, in meat-space the reality is this: I’ve started estrogen. It’s still early days, but in time its changes <em>will</em> become more and more apparent. If I wanted to hide my trans identity, I’m making all the wrong choices.</p>

<p>While I know there’s nothing wrong with being trans, there is still a part of me that feels <em>weird</em> about it. I feel like I’m doing something bad; like at any moment someone is going to burst through the doors and hand me a slip of paper summoning me to the principal’s office. Maybe they’ll call home to my parents! Or maybe I’ll be pulled aside at youth group on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Intellectually, I know these feelings are simply the remnants of misguided ideologies. Still, a part of me feels like a monster; a <em>freak</em>. Not only do I have to grapple with dysphoria, I also have to deal with the warped morality of a belief system I haven’t claimed for well over a decade—its roots run <em>deep</em>—invalidating and making me feel gross for having that dysphoria in the first place.</p>

<p>However, in the time since I began work on this post, I’ve made some headway into silencing that bigoted voice—hence this post standing on its own—but I may never be able to fully shut it up.</p>

<p>For years, I was taught to hate myself and people like me. There’s a lengthy section above detailing Christianity’s place in my story, and believe me, I could’ve written a <em>hell</em> (get it?) of a lot more. But ultimately, I don’t want to engage in fruitless hate-mongering, lest I stoop to the level of the very people I’m criticizing. However, I feel some clarification is needed:</p>

<p>I do not hate Christians. Believe what one will. I don’t presume that we found the truth of the universe a couple thousand years ago, but honestly, <em>no one really knows anything</em>. We’re all just blind fools making our best guesses at The Truth. I recognize that there are Christians that genuinely do practice acceptance and forgiveness, which is brilliant. With them, I have no quarrel. Having said that, I will never respect those that hide behind religious convictions to justify their pathetic bigotry and hatred—something we’re seeing quite a lot of at the moment. To those such individuals and their closely-held Nazi brethren: from the bottom of my heart, <em>fuck you</em>. History will not look kindly upon you.</p>

<p>With that, I think I’ve rambled for long enough. There will be plenty of time in the future for further musings on being trans or Autistic or whatever else.</p>

<p>Here’s to new beginnings.</p>

<p>Sage 🌿<br />
<del>they/them (for now)</del> she/they<br />
🏳️‍⚧️</p>

<h2 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments</h2>

<p>There’s a host of great resources out there for trans folk and those questioning, but it’s becoming increasingly difficult to find them. Below are some sites and creators that have helped me in my transition.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://genderdysphoria.fyi/en">The Gender Dysphoria Bible</a>: A brilliant deep-dive into the many types of dysphoria and the process of medically transitioning. This is a great resource even for those just seeking to learn more about trans people and our experiences.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://linktr.ee/ICKY">ICKY</a>: Icky’s YouTube videos and TikToks have been instrumental in my education on trans-related topics. She also has a <a href="https://bigicky.gumroad.com">great guide on HRT</a>!</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lilarallatos?_t=ZT-8tgKwezamsd&amp;_r=1">Lila</a>: I love this woman. Lila’s positivity is infectious. It’s a challenge to watch her TikToks and not smile. In moments when I felt like transitioning was an insurmountable hurdle, her optimism gave me the strength I needed to push forward.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/egg_irl/">r/egg_irl</a>: There are many subreddits with great LGBTQ+ communities, but this one in particular helped me come to terms with my identity.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBYlEnfAUbrYSwF0VujcmHA">TransVoiceLessons</a>: Look, I’m going to do my voice training <em>eventually</em>. When I do, I’ll be using <a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLYJkVI7LLpknvBww07jnsxbz-_Lkynsry&amp;si=glACCEloi3bCuNHE">Zheanna Erose’s lessons</a>. They are very well-structured and easy-to-follow, even for someone who has zero knowledge of what things like “resonance” are.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/">Erin In The Morning</a>: Erin and her team do fantastic work covering trans topics. Their work is absolutely vital in the current moment. I’ve especially appreciated <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/a-line-by-line-analysis-of-trumps">Erin’s breakdowns of</a> <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/a-line-by-line-analysis-of-trumps-760">Trump’s executive orders</a> and her <a href="https://www.erininthemorning.com/p/post-election-2024-anti-trans-risk">Trans Risk Assessment Map</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://hrtcafe.net/">HRT Cafe</a>: For those that need to start HRT but cannot do so due to various laws or restrictions, this site can help.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I’d like to extend a big thank-you to the clinic providing my HRT. I won’t link it here for privacy reasons, but it offered the easiest, most comfortable medical experience I’ve ever had. It was incredibly neurodivergent-friendly: The processes were laid-out clearly, and my (many) questions were answered with grace and without judgment. Notably, I never felt like I had to “prove” I am trans. I said I was trans and that was that—just as it should be.</p>

<p>Last but certainly not least, a very special thank-you to Jane Schoenbrun, Justice Smith, Jack Haven, and everyone else involved in the creation of <em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>. Your wonderful, beautiful film not only changed my life, but very likely saved it. 🩷</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Unless otherwise stated, all quotes in this piece are from <em>I Saw the TV Glow</em>. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>“For the wages of sin is death…” Romans 6:23 (NIV) <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Romans 3:23 (NIV) <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>I’m not sure why I thought referring to myself as “fruity” would defuse the situation. (Autistic naïvety, perhaps?) It just led to further ridicule, naturally. <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
      <p>Of course, not <em>all</em> the boys were toxic. Far from it, but those that were spoke the loudest. They set the tone for the rest of us. <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:6">
      <p>I once criticized my university’s mathematics program. It didn’t like that very much. <a href="#fnref:6" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:7">
      <p>HRT: hormone replacement therapy <a href="#fnref:7" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>sage-leaf</name></author><category term="trans" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I Saw the TV Glow, A24 strong language, anti-LGBTQ+ rhetoric Vague spoilers for I Saw the TV Glow. This is technically an addition to January’s post. However, this piece stands on its own. Read the prior post first… or don’t! Previously on “The Pink Opaque”]]></summary></entry></feed>